Welcome back! In the last section we talked about how
we have Google.com And if we enter an IP address
we essentially get all these files from Google so
if we look back at the diagram that we had we see
here that the Google servers just send us a couple
of files which are a HTML, CSS and Javascript, again
something that will cover later on.
But for now based on that knowledge
we should be able to break Google.
So let's play with something.
If you open up Google Chrome and you go into View,
then developer, then Developer Tools you're going to
have a screen over here that pops up.
You might want to move it up and
down just so you can see better.
And let me just scroll this down a bit so you
can see you'll see over here that there is
a little icon on the left
with a pointer in a window.
If you click on that and now go to the website
you'll see it selects a bunch of different things.
So it's just an element selector
so, let's just click on this.
So when I click on this it takes me to
the part of the HTML file that essentially
tells Google to put in Google search here.
So based on that, we can do something fun, we
can get the value over here of Google search.
And let's change it to 'Andrei's Search'.
Press Enter. Look at that - we have - we now just
changed Google to have 'Andrei's Search' over here.
That's very very cool.
I want to play around with
that and see what you can do.
For example if I now select this just like I don't
want this I'm going to press the delete key
and just delete it. Look at that!
I can delete that.
OK I don't like that either.
I'm going to press delete on that as well.
And let's see.
You know what on the entire website I
want this entire body thing gone delete.
Look at that.
We just completely deleted Google.
Now you must be freaking out.
"What happened?"
"Am I going to get sent to jail?",
"I just delete the Google!"; well,
no, not really,
press enter and Google is back.
Now why is that?
Well, if we go back to our diagram we have Google
servers and we were playing around with one of these
files and we just modified it we
essentially just said delete delete.
So Google was gone but when I made that
request again Google servers, 'no problem,
we have these files'.
They send these files all over again,
back to the server.
Hopefully that made sense to you we see that
the browser essentially is a tool - a piece
of software that can receive files from
servers and it knows how to read them.
So that, look at that, we get pretty Google and we can
type in all the searches that we want in the world.
All right let's get to the next section
where we talk about the Internet backbone.
See you on the next one! Bye-bye.