Hey they're welcome back.
All right if you thought so far
everything's been really really cool.
Well, things are gonna get a lot cooler.
We're going to be talking
about the Internet backbone.
So we recognize this because I've been talking
about it for the last couple of lessons.
But some of you may have had a question
that is what do the arrows mean.
I mean it's kind of like magic right.
I just told you that we send off the IP address to
the servers the server responds with some files but
this is just magic like what do these arrows mean?
So, we're going to talk about that in this lesson.
And we're going to do that with this really, really
fuzzy diagram that I found online from this website.
It's not the clearest picture but it actually has
some really important things so I want to use that
to demonstrate to you what
the Internet backbone is.
So, as some of you know the way we connect in our homes,
at a coffee shop, or at work is we usually have
Wi-Fi or you know maybe sometimes we still have people
they are using Ethernet cables
and connecting through those.
But for now let's just focus on the fact that we have
a home and we have Wi-Fi and this Wi-Fi essentially
gives us Internet from the router.
You can see this little person over here working hard
with a router next to him and this router is connected
all the way to something called a modem.
And this is something that if you ever sign up for
Internet or change providers you most likely had
somebody come to your house
and install something.
And that's this box over here that
essentially allows the ISP the Internet
Service Provider,
this big building over here,
we remember that, to connect to it.
So this modem has the signal
towers that transmit signals of,
you know Google.com and it receives these messages
and then this is why I picked this image just
because I think it's incredible you see this wire
that is connected all the way to the ISP and then
the Internet Service Provider, the ISP is connected to
this magical blue cable that is the Internet backbone
and something that's really important in this image
is the fact that there's Wi-Fi which is over the
air but at the end of the day everything
is kind of connected through cables.
So some of you or many of you,
or all of you might be wondering
"What the hell is this Internet
backbone thing?"
Sounds cool. But this - this is kind of vague, so I found a
really, really cool - cool thing that we can do together
I'll post this website in
the notes after this lesson.
But if you go over here you actually see the Internet
backbone. So, let's say we're in Brazil and we want
to search Google.com.
Well from Brazil, from our home, through Wi-Fi, it
connects to our router, to our modem and then all the way
to our Internet Service Provider lets say (the) Internet
service provider is over here and then, through
cables it connects all the way to, let's say this point
over here, and let's say, for now that the Google
servers are located somewhere
in Portugal over here.
Well that signal of me looking for that IP address of
Google and looking for those Google files is going
to go through this submarine cable.
Yeah, you heard that right.
It's a physical cable that goes at the bottom of the
sea floor from Brazil all the way to Portugal where
the Google servers are.
And then the Google server says yep I got those
files here there are and sends it all the way back.
Through the ISP all the
way back to our house.
Isn't that cool that there's physical cables that are
connecting, and creating the Internet so you know
there are times where somebody destroys or something
happens where these cable connections are cut off
and you sometimes lose
internet connection that way.
But yeah the Internet backbone is literally just
this network all over the world of connected cables
so that we can transfer these
files all over the world.
And just to show you how insane this is somebody from the
Opte Project over here - I got this off of Wikipedia,
mapped out, and I believe this was in 2015, just 30
percent of the network, and you can see over here that
each one of these dots is an IP address.
So, a computer that is connected to another
computer, that is connected to another computer.
And that's the Internet.
The Internet is just all these connected computers
that are just transferring files between each other
and as web developers and
this is the coolest thing.
And that's why I just think everybody should
be a web developer because it's so cool.
You're allowing this to happen.
You're allowing this transferring of files from one
computer to another, transferring knowledge from
Brazil to Portugal and all over the world and you get to
be part of it - you get to be part of this networking
and get to evolve.
When this picture of the Internet came to
me I knew that this was the career for me.
So, hopefully that gets you
excited in the next session.
I'm going to show you
something really cool.
Traceroute before we finish up the lesson and we get
into the next sections so hope that was cool see
in the next one.