And welcome back to the second
'Web-developer Fundamentals'.
Another very important aspect
of being a web developer
and that is the fact that we
have multiple web browsers.
Now if you remember Tim Berners-Lee the inventor of
the worldwide web created it because we needed a
standard way to share documents amongst each other,
and through HTML, CSS and Javascript we're able
to read these files and actually
have beautiful websites.
Now, when we send these files over
Each of these browsers
read the HTML, CSS, and Javascript,
and layout the web-page for us.
But as you can see each one of them is owned
by a company, and is a different browser.
So that means they all have to agree on how they're
going to read the HTML, CSS, and Javascript, because
if they don't all agree, then well, we need to create
different files specific for each browser, because
each one of them has a different idea
of what HTML, CSS, and Javascript is.
And you know what?
When the World Wide Web got started we had something
called, 'the browser wars' where each browser was
kind of doing its own thing
implementing different things.
And we still have that to this day, to some extent,
there is a governing body which kind of creates
the standards now. But it is still a pain point
for developers, where we need to figure out that
whenever we send our files to the web browser, it all
looks the same. And that is one of the biggest problems
we have as developers and you'll see tools later
on in this course that try to solve that issue.
But you'll always encounter this problem, where we
want to make sure that wherever your browser gets
rendered, anybody can see your website, and not only
that we also have mobile phones now that access
the Internet.
We have iPads.
So now, not only do we have to worry about different
browsers, and whether they agree on what code works
in each of these files.
We also have to make sure that our web sites look
good on small screens on big screens on all sorts
of different screens, and that is a very important
concept something that, when you get to become a web
-developer you'll encounter this problem where you
have to test on each device, each browser to make
sure everything works. And we'll use some tools that
have developed over the years to solve these problems
so that it's not as much as a pain
point as it is or as it was. All right,
one more lesson to go and then we're going
to get coding. See you on the other side.