Let's talk about how this course will look like
for you.
Each section has some sort of actionable steps
that you are able to follow such as building websites
and sample projects and everything we use in this course
is a tool that companies use in real life.
They're the best of the best.
So let's look at the course outline.
The first part will be an introduction.
Some basic concepts to get us familiar with the web
and how it works.
We will start off with how the internet works
what is the history of these technologies.
We're going to talk about the history of the web,
the web browsers and I'll actually have you understand
the underlying concepts of the Internet and how the technologies
we have now have come to be where they are.
And then we're going to learn HTML5.
Finally building our first website we'll also get into some
advanced HTML where we're going to build
some complex forms and get you really really good at this technology.
We will then move into CSS which allows us to style our websites and make them beautiful.
Afterwards we'll get into advanced CSS
and using CSS3 features like transitions and gradients in
the advanced CSS section we'll create
a background generator project that is going to be a lot of fun.
Once we've mastered how to work with websites
using HTML and CSS will then start learning about
Bootstrap, templates and building your own startup landing page that accepts e-mails and will actually
store the e-mails of users as people
who are interested in your startup.
A very useful skill that
you will definitely need in your career.
Or if you have a business idea
that you want to pursue.
We will also dive into newer features of CSS
like flexbox my favorite CSS grid and get really really
good at doing responsive layouts with CSS.
Finally we finish off part one
with career of a developer.
What does a career of a developer
actually entail.
What are the salaries.
What are the differences between a software developer,
mobile developer, software engineer, full stack
developer.
We're going to cover all that
and we're also going to talk about the future trends and what skills do
you need in the future. From part one
we move to our next section in here we'll start to introduce
JavaScript and learn concepts that allow us to learn
a real programming language and the most popular
programming language which is JavaScript.
We then move to DOM manipulation
where we'll actually use JavaScript to create actions and behaviors
to our websites.
So they're interactive.
And then finally we're going to learn some
advanced JavaScript concepts so that we can use JavaScript
to control the machines around us.
Now just knowing HTML, CSS and JavaScript
is not good enough and you won't be able to grow in your
role and command a higher salary just with those three skills.
I'm going to be teaching you these things coming up
because these are the things you should know so
that you are miles ahead of the rest.
So after the JavaScript section we're going to start
getting into the command line and working with
the terminal.
We then learn about developer environments
and I'll actually show you what my developer environment
on my computer looks like when I'm working.
We'll be setting up our own computers
with all the tools necessary of a real life developer so you can
use the same setup when you go and work
for somebody or for yourself.
We will then learn about Git and GitHub.
Probably the most important tools of a developer
and I'll show you how teams work with these technologies
to create collaborative software.
We then get into a fun section
which is a day in the life of a developer.
I'll show you what a day today from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m.
what it looks like and what tools you'll use.
I will take you through a sample day at a tech company
just so that's on your first day of the job.
You won't be surprised.
We will then jump to NPM and NPM scripts
a way for developers to share their code and it's going to
open up a whole world of possibilities in this section.
We're also going to create
our own customizable portfolio project.
So moving forward you can add the projects from this course
to your website and have it as your online
resume.
Finally we finish off part two with React.js
You'll learn the library that companies like
Netflix, Facebook and Instagram used to build fast
scalable applications.
This is one of the highest
in demand skills in the industry.
It's so much fun.
And I'm really really excited about
that section from part two.
We'll move on to the world outside of just the front-end
and we're going to learn about HTTP JSON AJAX
something that will open up
a world of possibilities.
We'll learn about the back-end basics
and what back-end developers do.
And then finally I'll introduce you to some APIs
what APIs are and definitely some really interesting
APIs that are out there.
This section is really going to open up your world
from just being a front-end developer that is really
good at building websites to somebody
that can create really dynamic applications.
And it will set us up for Part 4.
This is where it gets really really fun.
We're gonna start working on our final project called
smart brain and we're gonna start off by working
on the front-end that is using
CSS, JavaScript, HTML and react.
We're going to build an image recognition app
that's gonna be really really fun.
You submit a URL and using a machine learning API
we're gonna detect to see if in that photo there
is a face and then detect where that faces with a square box.
We're gonna create a sign-in form a registration form
and it's gonna be really really impressive something
that you're gonna be able to use in your portfolio
and impress future employers or clients.
We then take a break from the smart brain project to introduce you to Node.js and Express.
This is where I show you how to build a server
how to create a RESTful API so that when we get into
the next section the smart brain server section
we build our own server so that we're actually able
to communicate with the server over HTTP
and sign in to our app sign out have profiles and do all sorts
of really interesting things. From there
we again take a break and learn about databases
a really complex topic but I'm going to make it simple
for you to understand how they work and in the next section
we're actually going to create our own database
using Postgres and connected to our server
so that at the end you'll have a fully working app that
has a front-end client website, a back-end server
and a server that's working with a database. Pretty
much a full fledged application.
And finally we're going to deploy and launch
that application so you know exactly how to put a real
life app that is secure and won't get hacked on the web
and don't worry I'm going to provide all files
for you throughout the sections so that you can just
add them to your portfolio or you can work along
the videos as well depending on
what your learning style is.
You can follow along whichever way
works best for you.
And at the end of the course I'm also going to have
a quick little section of some of my favorite resources
to get hired.
Some of my own advice on finding a job of your dreams.
By the end of this course you're going to learn
the skills that allow you to apply
for jobs in the following roles:
web developer, software developer, front-end developer,
javascript developer or a full-stack developer
You're going to learn the technologies that are
actually being used behind tech companies.
You're going to be able to build
your own websites and applications.
But most importantly you're going to master
fundamental concepts in web development so that it sets
you up for a bright long career.
I also want to make this course interactive.
I'll be making videos of student projects and what others
have built in this course like you.
I'll also have Q&amp;A videos where based on the most popular questions
or the most popular topics I'm
going to create new videos as they are suggested.
We have a lot to cover but it's gonna be a lot of fun.
Let's get started.