Welcome back.
In this section we're gonna be talking about some advanced topics in CSX and I'm going to start off
with the critical render path.
What is that.
Well we always should know how things work underneath the hood so we can make our websites as fast and
reliable as possible.
So based on what we've built in the previous section let's look at what's happening underneath the hood.
We are going to our Web site and ideally our Web site will be on a server and I'll show you how to do
that later on in the course.
For now is just our computer.
But let's pretend we have a server where our files are hosted.
When we go to our Web site we'll call it cool Web site dot com.
We request the HP email file and the browser now sees our HCM Alpha reads through this document and
as it's looking through it notices that oh I need a c assess file here so it goes back.
Makes Another request and says Hey can you please give me a c file as well the server says yep no problem.
Let me grab that for you.
Grabs the C Ss file and now it starts looking at both the AC L and the C assess file to try and figure
out how the web page should look.
But then it also notices that hold on a second.
I need some fonts as well.
So it goes to this address and looks for a font.
Again the Web site now asks the Web site that the fonts our host that act in our case is the Google
API and it grabs the font file.
Now here's the thing.
While it's grabbing the font file it could render the page and rendering means displaying so it could
display the Web site if it only has the ACM on CSX.
But it might not show up the text because the text is looking for the font file.
So when we talk about the critical render path we like to mention that CSX is their render blocking
file so you won't be able to render a web page until you receive your CSX.
And sometimes if you have font files you'll also have to wait for the text to render on the page so
keep that in mind when you build your Web sites.
But what are things that we can consider when doing this so that our Web sites load up faster.
One is maybe to have our own fun files.
Another one might be that you don't want to make your CSX too big.
If we had hundreds and hundreds of lines of code of CSX while the file gets bigger and bigger and it's
more and more that you have to transfer over the wire one method that people have used and you'll see
often is something called magnifying your CSX.
And if we open up a browser here you can do something called CSX magnify and CSX minute by what it does
is you can enter your CSX here you can see an example over here.
So you enter this and you click minute five and one minute five does it removes all the whitespace so
everything is on one line just really tiny together.
So even though it's the same CSX it technically makes the file a little bit smaller so that the number
of bytes that you're sending over the Internet is a lot less and you'll see that technique used in JavaScript
as well.
And we'll talk about that in that section but that is the critical render path a path that a Web site
takes to display something to the user.
I'll see in the next one by.