Lou let's build a fun image portfolio site.
One of the biggest problems that people have and the hardest problems to assess it's always making sure
that we have our items displayed in the location that we want.
That is a really really difficult problem.
And there are many many solutions to this problem but one of the new ways and now is probably the most
popular way is called flex box and we're gonna be using that to create a beautiful image Web site.
Let's get started.
So I have an indexation mollified here and a style that's the SS file in the same directory on my desktop
so let's get started with our typical HMO file.
Title I see SS and in the body we're going to have a header of life in the wild and refresh.
Perfect.
And in here we're going to have a div with that class of container.
We'll close that off and in here let's add some images.
Now if you remember with images I can type in this.
And then tab with sublime text and we don't have any pictures yet.
So for now let's just copy and paste and add six images
save and refresh.
OK.
Let's start adding some of these images and actually have a file full of these images for you and I'll
attach it to the next lesson so you can also build it yourself.
So I'm just gonna copy these.
Quickly
who knows a lot of copy and pasting.
Let's save that and refresh.
All right.
We have our images and they're massive.
So let's make this a little bit smaller.
We can now go to our style sheet and we can select the images and let's just do width 450 pixels and
height 300 pixels and you might be asking yourself how come we don't do it here on the individual images.
Remember we can add attributes but that means if we needed to ever change anything we have to individually
go into each image and change it versus just changing in one location.
So for now we're going to stick to the CSX size.
Let's save that and refresh.
And obviously we need to link the file so let's add a link here and it will reference our style dot
CSX say that and refresh.
There you go.
We have our images like that.
Some beautiful animals here now flex box has a great resource
obviously from CSX tricks and this is pretty much all you need.
It shows you all the things that flex box can do and as you can see it allows you to play around with
content and shift it around in a very nice way.
I'm going to attach this link for you the end of this video and you can take a look for yourself.
For now let's learn a few flex box properties.
We want to define that everything inside of this div is part of flex box.
It's called container so let's do container.
And within this container we will say that display will be flex.
So that's how we activate flex box refresh.
OK.
We have a few changes which is nice but I don't want to scroll through this.
Ideally I can see everything without scrolling.
So if one thing we want to do and again we can look down over here at the suggestion we see that flex
wrap might be something that we want to add so let's do flex wrap and do wrap save and refresh.
OK that's perfect so if I make this bigger you see that everything is wrapping around OK but I think
the continents should be centered it kind of looks weird to having everything to the left over here.
So again we can do something called justify content and then we can do center and refresh.
Perfect.
And we if we look on the guide over here justify content should be right over here and can see all the
properties that it has that looks pretty good.
And we did that pretty fast made a nice little portfolio website already.
What else can we add now that we have this flexible container around our Web site.
Let's make the header a little bit prettier than it is now.
So that's the H1 we can had an H1 here and we'll say that the font family is like this one fancy save
and refresh.
Well I like that one font size let's make it a little bit bigger.
We'll do three E M so if you don't remember what E M is.
Make sure you check out the video.
OK.
So that looks better.
Maybe I'll be nice to have a bit of a border as well so we can do border bottom because we only want
a border on the bottom and we'll do two pixels solid pink and refresh OK.
Perfect.
That looks good.
But ideally I want a border just around this I don't want the entire section so we can actually just
say that for each one we want the width to be 400 pixels save and refresh.
All right.
Perfect.
That looks good.
And ideally this is centered so that the line underneath it is well on the left side and right side
is equally distributed so we can do something like text align center
and you'll notice here that it's aligned in the center but not the web page center.
It's a line in the center of the width of 400 pixels but that looks good would be actually nice to have
a border on here as well.
So let's add border right to pixels solid pink save and refresh.
All right that looks very nice then the final thing I want to add is I want to have some spacing between
these images so I'm going to add a margin of 10 pixels here and refresh.
All right.
Let's take a look at our Web site right now
that looks very very nice.
As you can see flex box is a very easy thing to implement and it makes your Web sites look really really
nice and you can position your content very easily especially if you have these container like structures.
I want to show you one last resource for Flex box.
Again this is a tool that you'll see more and more of and ideally you'll build the Web sites using flex
box instead of some of the older ways.
One way to get really really good a flex box is to play this game.
And it's called flex box from me I believe.
Let's see and here you're trying to get the frog onto the leaf.
It's a little home so you can do something like justify content flex and look at that.
You get the frog onto the leaf and you move on to the next round.
I'll leave this for you.
It's a really really good way to learn flex box.
I think this is probably the best way to do layout and see.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.