Welcome back.
In this video we're going to be talking about CSX three now just like with a CML in 80 mile five.
CSX is a standard that constantly evolves to adapt to new demands of Web sites so CSX 3 is the latest
evolution of CSX where we've added new properties and new features so that we can make our design even
better.
So if you remember in our diagram over here all these browsers have different developers different teams
that work on implementing their features.
Now in an ideal world everybody agrees on what CSX does and when new features and new properties are
added.
Everybody implements them at the same time but that's simply not the case.
Some browsers might work with some property.
Some might not because they haven't gotten around to making it work.
So let's go back to our Web site now.
Let's play with one of my favorite CSX three properties.
How cool would it be if when we hover over these pictures the picture moves well with CSX three they've
introduced something called transition.
And if I do all one second and I'll explain to what that does in one second image hover.
So this should be familiar where when we hover we want the image to transform.
This is a new property as well.
And we'll say scale one point one.
So let's see what happens.
I refresh look at that my images are now moving on hover.
Is that cool.
What these properties do is say that I want the image to transition when an action is taken upon it.
And I want all the properties to transition over one second And what's that transition going to be.
Well when I hover I wanted to transform by a scale of one point one.
So it's essentially growing.
If I change this to four seconds and I refresh.
Well now takes four seconds for the image to scale.
You can see over here.
I'm going to change this back to one second just because it looks better that way.
If I make this website full screen you see that we now have a beautiful effect for our image gallery.
There's also another property called animation which you can look at on your own.
But again CSX tree has brought in a lot of these new properties to make Web sites even more dynamic
than they are now.
But there is a little caveat to using such properties and that is you want to make sure that each browser
has implemented a new feature so if I go to one of our favorite Web sites w schools they have a CSX
browser support reference and here you can look at all the CSX to make sure that browsers support whatever
property you want to use.
So if we go to transition we see that it is supported by all latest browsers but you also see that if
we go to something like a user select they have this M.S. Moore's Web kids line over it.
And if we scroll all the way down we'll show you that it is supported by Internet Explorer with prefix
M.S..
What does that mean.
Well these are browser prefixes and you'll see them every once in a while.
What it is is these are new features of CSX that haven't fully been implemented by the browsers and
you want to use a prefix to make sure that they work as an experimental feature in the browser.
Let me explain what that means if I wanted to add a let's say a box shadow Suzanne means kind of making
this look 3-D and having a shadow underneath the edge over here.
Previously I had to do something like this where I put box shadow and you can read into the property
to see what I'm about to do but I'm going to do four pixels four pixels five pixels and then the color
which is a bit of a gray.
So if I do this and refresh Well now it looks nice and my browser is the new chrome so it has this feature
but a few years ago when box shadow was first introduced you had to do something like this box shadow
then copy and paste this and this makes sure that it works on the Mozilla browser.
And then you also had and this which made sure that it works on Internet Explorer you had Web Kit which
made sure that it works on safari and chrome.
And then finally you also had oh which made it work on the Opera browser and then you also had to still
mention the box shadow without the prefix is at the bottom.
So now if any of these browsers don't support box shadow well they have these prefixes so that it should
work and book Shadow has been some time now so you don't need to do this anymore.
But there is one great way of seeing if a certain property still needs browser prefixes and that is
using something like this reference which I will leave for you so you can check it out.
Another thing I wanted to show you is can I use.
So can I use dot com.
He is a great resource to see any thing that you might want to try out.
So if I type in here a CSX transition you'll see CSX three transitions are supported in all these browsers
except we have one Opera Mini.
And it says it's two point sixty three percent of the global usage.
So if you use CSX three transitions two point sixty three percent of population might not be able to
see it.
Now whether that is your user base or not you can kind of decide what the tradeoffs are.
But this is a great thing to use and if we use something like flex box while we see that flex box has
all support it shouldn't be a problem for you to use it.
OK let's go back to this and just finish up this Web site to make it look nice so I don't like that
there's space here ideally.
This is all the way to the left but if I do margin 0 pixels and I refresh that actually doesn't change
much because sometimes browsers have their own default margins.
So the way to get around it is to do margin zero for the body.
So margin 0 pixels let's save and refresh.
Perfect.
Now we have this all the way to the left.
OK.
But we do want a bit of a buffer at the top so I'm going to add margin top and we'll do 10 pixels save
and refresh.
Perfect.
Now we have a beautiful Web site and it didn't really take us much.
We just wrote a few lines of CSX a few lines of 80 email and because we have let's see in the next one
by.