And welcome back.
Whenever you have a request from an employer to build a website or a web app one of the first things
that they will ask for is to make sure that your Web site is responsive.
So what is responsive UI.
Well I can show you by opening up the developer tools which we should know by now and you'll see over
here that there is a little phone icon.
If we click on this go we'll show you why your Web site will look like on say an iPhone.
Let's make this a little bit bigger.
So let's do 100 percent of the size.
Perfect.
You'll see that your Web site on an iPhone looks like this.
And if we do a night bad well it looks like this and if it rotates it looks good so responsive means
that your Web site no matter what whether it's on the big screen or something like a notepad it is responsive.
That means there's no cut offs.
Everything looks good no matter what size the screen is.
So if we go back to our Web site and close the developer tabs I can actually play around with this open
and close and see that it's responsive.
The Web site looks good no matter what the size and users can enjoy the experience and not be turned
off because whether they're accessing it through their eye bad at home on their couch it still looks
good.
So keep that in mind.
Responsive UI should be a priority when building Web sites.
I'll see in the next one probably.