Hello.
This is your new robot friend and I have a fun little challenge for you.
I've created this robot that is actually pretty cool.
So as you hover his head grows big and he can also dance.
Now here's the challenge I've created majority of this robot.
But you first need to assemble it.
So it looks like this.
I've left a few files for you.
An index file and a CSX file.
The only problem is that these parts are all over the page and I need you to assemble them so that you
can have a robot friend as well in the following section.
After the exercise I'll have the solution that you can use but give it a try and hopefully you'll have
a new robot friend to.