Welcome back!
In this section I want to
tackle the problem that we have
especially when we're starting out
that is "How do I create
a layout of a website?".
And it's probably the hardest thing
to learn when you're starting off.
How do you create something let's
say like this that is responsive that
we see all across the web.
A navigation bar, a header,
some grids, a footer down here.
And how do we really make it responsive?
In this section we're going to
build an ideal webpage layout.
So that moving forward you
have the baseline and fondation
to go off and customize and build whatever
sites you want that are responsive without
spending a lot of time trial and error trying
different things with CSS hoping that it works.
So I'm going to show you my
recommended way of laying out web pages
that is responsive and have that
template available to you moving forward.
We're also going to learn about a
new feature in CSS called CSS grid
which is a really really powerful.
And as you learn allows us to use
this CSS grid combined with flexbox
to honestly not even need
things like Bootstrap 4
or other libraries that
allow you to do grids.
Back in the day, it was really
really hard to do layout and in CSS.
But with tools like CSS
grid and flexbox you now
have the ability to really build beautiful
responsive layouts really really fast.
So let's get started.
See you in the next video.