Welcome back!
When it comes to layout using CSS
a very important skill of a developer
there are probably
three really good ways to do it this year.
One is something that we've
discussed and that is flexbox.
Another one was Bootstrap 4 and we're going to
learn about a new way of doing it which is called
CSS grid and if you go for a google image search
and type in something like CSS flexbox vs. grid
you're going to get a lot of images explaining what
the differences are why you use one over the other.
But I want to just preface the next couple of
videos and let you know that there's no one versus
the other one that wins out over the other.
There's always a tradeoff.
And the best way to think about these tools is as
complimentary tools that is the both work really really
well together.
You don't only have to use just fluxbox or just see
a set script ideally use them both together and
I'll show you later on how we can use both fluxbox
and CSS grid to pretty much do anything we want.
When it comes to layout but just to start us off
a good way to think about flexbox vs. CSS grid
is that Flexbox is really good to
use if you just have one dimension.
Maybe you're only thinking about columns
and how to do layout based on columns.
CSS grids are really really powerful especially when
it comes to two dimensional layouts that is both
columns and rows.
So it's really really good at let's say image galleries
or listing out your portfolio projects on your
own personal webpage
and we'll get into that.
But now you might be asking yourself OK
isn't this what Bootstrap allows us to do.
And you'd be right.
Bootstrap came at a time when we
didn't have flexbox and CSS grid.
It came at a time when we just had display and
floats and positioning CSS properties that as we saw
are really really difficult to use when it comes
to layouts and Bootstrap solved that problem.
It gave us this grid system that we can use within
Bootstrap to make really beautiful layouts.
So that was really really useful.
But on your resume if you say that you know Bootstrap
4 yeah that's good but it won't be that impressive
to employers anymore especially if you're going for
a real developer job which is why I haven't focused
too much on Bootstrap 4. Because I argue that everything
that you can do in Bootstrap 4 although sometimes
it's easy because it comes with their own pre-built
components you can do now using flexbox and
CSS grid and because being a good developer
means not just learning one library that always
changes always evolves.
It's learning the fundamentals.
It's more important for us to learn flexbox and CSS
grid because now if we know these two we can create
any sort of layouts we want.
One last thing when it comes
to CSS grid it's a new feature.
Most web browsers have support for it but we do see
a few reds and older versions of browsers that do
not support CSS grid.
When we look at flexbox it's a little bit better
because it's older than CSS grid and we've learned
all about this before right.
Each browser has their own implementation and any
new feature has to be implemented individually.
So although CSS grid has become pretty standard across
the web if you're trying to support older browsers
or something like Opera Mini then you might
want to consider using floats to do layout.
Although to be honest most of the web
is moving toward CSS grid and flexbox.
So I just recommend starting to use this right away
because eventually this will have really really
good support but enough talk.
I think it's time for us to learn CSS grids to see
what all the hype is about and start working on
a fun little project.
I'll see in the next one. Bye bye.