Welcome back.
Let's talk about individual items
now when it comes to CSS grid.
Because up until now we've just used this container
and performed operations or changed views to all
the items.
But what if we wanted a bit of a funky
grid system that has a different size.
In that case we can just select
individual items within this container.
If we go back to our HTML page we see that we have
these zones but each zone has different color.
So let's use one of these colors for example green
which we have two of to have some special CSS grid
properties so let's have a green class and I'm just
going to do it up here instead of at the bottom
just so we can keep all the
CSS grid things up the top.
Now for individual items I can say something like
grid-column and say what we wanted to do in terms
of the column grid system and the way this works is we
can give it where it should start and where it should
end.
What does that mean?
Well if I do grid-column-start and I say 1 and then
have grid-column-end and I give it 2 and I refresh
the page nothing changes.
What if I do 'grid-column-end: 3' and I
refresh. Whoa! What just happened here?
In order for us to understand
what these numbers mean.
Let's open up the
developer tools once again.
I'm going to select the items and as we'll see over
here we see that we have a grid zone and this fox
is now taking up two grid spaces.
In the way CSS grid works.
It has a numbering system where
the first line over here is one.
The second line over here is
two and then this is three.
Let's just make this a
little bit bigger to show you
and that's better.
We now have three grid
systems or three grid items.
We have one here.
When the first one begins two where the second one
begins and then 3 where the third one begins.
So what we're saying here is that when it comes to
columns start at one which is right over here and
then end at three so that if I do four here and I
refresh you see that it now covers the entire length.
But as soon as we make
it a little bit bigger.
Well it only is going to cover the
1, 2, 3 up to 4.
And if we make it a little bit smaller
you see that because we said one to four it doesn't
actually make it as responsible as it was before and it
actually extends to make sure that it fills in one
to four and there's a shorthand way of doing this
instead of saying grid-column-start and grid-column-end
we can just say grid-column and then give it the
start number and then slash the end number so that
if I refresh you see that it's the same thing.
Let's make this a little bit bigger and let's
just do three here just to keep it small.
All right.
I'm going to close this and we
see that our grid items now have.
Well this looks pretty good actually.
We have the green classes
that spanned over more grids.
Now a trick here is that sometimes we just
simply don't know what the user is going to see.
And we might want to spend the entire length
without having you know the rabbit come in.
And then the frog and the line coming and we can
actually do at the end here something like '-1'
which means all the way till the end.
If I refresh here, there you go
and make this larger and smaller.
We see that we are saying start at one and
then keep going all the way until the end.
And CSS grid '-1' signifies
the end of the viewport.
So that now we see that we have a nice responsive grid
again that just adjusts according to our viewport.
Very very cool now.
Sometimes we don't really know how many grids we're
going to have on our page and we also might not
necessarily wanted to spend it all across from beginning
to end so useful syntax here is to do something
like 'span 2' which says
span across two grids.
If I refresh here you see that
green is spanning across two grids.
If I do three it's going
to span across three grids.
And as you can imagine the default
is span 1 spanning across one.
But the interesting thing about this is if I do
say span 2 and I refresh as this gets smaller
you see that it's always going to span across to
make sure that it covers whatever the two grids are
which is once again very useful.
Finally we can also do
the same thing with rows.
If we do grid rows or grid row.
I can say, well, we wanted to span to start at
let's say one and end at three. If I refresh here
well what just happened here.
Well let's take a look.
We started at one and ended at three.
And because green is also this unicorn over here it
automatically moved it all the way up because we
wanted to start at one as well.
And remember our grid system now is row.
And if I open the developer tools and select the
grid one starts here then two then three right here
where it ends.
So you have to be careful with the positioning here
that this is going to move whatever it needs to.
All the way up to 1
but we're able to move things
around and adjust the rows as well.
Very very cool! Our grid system is
starting to look really really nice.
Let's do a bit more in the next video.