And welcome back.
I want to show you a property that is commonly used with images so I have a really funny picture here
of an alpaca.
So we're gonna copy that.
Actually we're gonna use the link for this and we're gonna add an image to our Web site.
Let's just make our font size a little bit smaller.
Perfect.
And I'm going to try and add a picture to the left over here.
So if we go to our about page and in our section over here we can try and add a picture.
So let's do an image tag.
And if you remember we have a source and that source I just copy and pasted the link and if I saved
this and refresh.
That's a big picture.
So as you may remember we have to do with close to 50 pixels and height 50 pixels let's save and refresh
and you can see that we broke.
Let's make that a little bit bigger actually.
Let's to two hundred and 200.
Perfect.
You can see here that we actually broke a bit of our CSX and that is because if you look over here we
have used this selector which says immediate neighbour of H2.
We can just do this for now refresh.
And there you have it.
But I kind of want the text to be on the right side over here.
How do we do that.
Well we can select the image and use a property called float and float.
You can do right or left.
So if we do left and refresh it flows the image to the left and you see that the text wraps around and
this property was created specifically for these reasons to have images floating to either left or right
and be able to have text wrapped around them you'll see instances where float is being used for positioning
elements and that's not the best practice because it has some funny properties.
For now just use it with images if you can.
And just to show you that I can do it on the right as well I go like this and refresh it flows to the
right kind of like this better so we'll keep that there so after the image we want to have a
in this footer l say Web site made with love close that safe.
And we also want to make this actually a lot smaller so I'm going to do five pixels because I want to
show you something.
So you see over here I've made this line had very very small but I wanted to demonstrate for you because
this is floated to the right.
Everything just kind of tax on to the left side over here.
And if we wanted to make sure that our footer is at the bottom of the website we would have to use a
property that almost always comes with float and it's usually put in the property after the float is
being used.
So in our case footer and we have to specify clear both.
So if I save and refresh we have that at the bottom and let's align it to the center here and let's
two center save and refresh.
Perfect.
Now we have Web site made with love with a whole bunch of gibberish.
But I want to show you that property float for images and make sure that we clear so that any property
that you don't want a part of the float is cleared so it can start on its own pass the image we'll see
in the next one.
But by.