Welcome back.
In this video I want to talk about the box model and CSX.
It's a very important concept and it's something that you might have been kind of curious in the back
of your head about and that is this image right here in CSX.
We have this idea of the box model which has the content it has the padding the border which we've seen
before.
And then the margin.
So we're going to talk about that in this video.
So we have our not so pretty web site right now.
But I have left intentionally our log in page still kind of blank and you see that there's no styles
applied to it because if we go to the log in page and a drag it over here it's referencing style too
which doesn't have much Stiles happening yet to really emphasize this point I wanted to just instead
of the law at Epsom I'm going to create a div if I give this a class of box model I can go into my style
to which I'm going to drag over here and I can say box model border five pixels solid red I save this
and refresh OK.
So we have our box model.
Let's add something into this div we have a.
And right now it's covering the entire space but if we add three more divs we'll call this one B the
next on C save and refresh.
OK.
We have these and if we wanted them all in one line then you might remember that that was display in
line block and I save refresh and there we have it.
OK.
Let's talk about the box model here.
Let's say we wanted more space inside of these for the letters.
Well in that case we can use something like padding so padding I can put 20 pixels save and refresh
and there's our padding.
But let's say we want a different padding so that the sides are wider than the top.
In that case we can do something like five pixels of the top 20 pixels on the right side five pixels
at the bottom and 20 pixels to the left eye refresh and look at that.
And that's just the standard that you'll have to get used to it's Top Right Bottom Left.
You can also actually do padding as you can see in the dropped on bottom left top right to specify.
But this is a quicker way of doing it.
If you remember there is one more and that was margin.
So margin allows us to create space outside of the border.
So if I go 20 pixels here and I save refresh you can see that we created 20 pixels on the left side
and right side but also the top and the bottom.
Let's say we only want spaces between the boxes but not at the top and bottom well same principle again.
We can do zero pixels 20 pixels zero pixels and 20 pixels so Top Right Bottom Left safe and refresh.
There you go.
Now this might get tedious.
Here is one other shorthand way and that is you can remove this.
So this means top and bottom.
This means left and right.
I say this and refresh.
Nothing should change.
And it doesn't.
And we can do the same at the top here as well.
Perfect.
One last thing I want to show you is that if we open up our developer tools so again we do inspect you'll
see in our styles that we have our box model.
So if you see over here we have our content.
We have our padding.
And it says 20 pixels five pixels five pixels.
We have our border five pixels five pixels five pixel five pixels.
And then our margin zero with 20 on the side.
So again chrome allows you to browse around and make sure that all of these are properly done.
The last thing you might ask is What about this content.
How can I change this.
And that's very simple you can do something like with this to 33 pixels save and refresh and also do
height to 55 pixels save and refresh and you'll see over here that in our box model we now have the
content with 33 pixels by 55 pixels.
All right that's it for now.
See in the next one.
By.