Welcome back.
Before we finish off the section I wanted to show you one last thing and that is up until this point.
We've used pixels quite a lot but there's two other options that we can actually use.
So let's remove our box models for now and instead let's create some paragraphs so using our lawn shorthand
and let's close this off.
Perfect.
Let's say that we also wanted to have a another paragraph that says introduction save and refresh.
And there you go.
We have our paragraph.
Now if we wanted to add some class to this paragraph we can just go in here and we don't need the box
models so we can delete that.
We can do something like P and let's do font size and for font size I've shown you that we can do percentages
but you can also do pixels so let's say 20 pixels save and refresh and we have pixels.
OK so let's say I want Laura Smithson to be a little bit bigger so we can use span again.
That's kind of like the diff tag that you've seen before is just good for inline.
So again this way we can add styles so I save that go to styles.
And now we can still expand and we can do something like this.
We can do font size five year refresh.
So what it's saying is we want the font size to be equal to five times the containing element which
is 20 pixels because if you remember we're inside of a p tag just to show you that that is right.
If I do 100 pixels and save and refresh that's the same so E M is kind of nice because if I do something
like two E.M. and refresh.
Well if I change this to Ten pixels and I refresh.
This always stays relative to the p one other one I can show you is R E M and that is the size in relation
to the size of the root element.
What is the root element.
Well it's the HMO.
So whatever the document is it's always going to be twice as big.
So if I do five refresh that's great but if I change the font size over here if five.
That won't be affected at all.
Good job getting this far in the course.
I know I've thrown a lot of properties and selectors at you but I promise in the next section we're
going to start building some real web sites and have fun with all this knowledge.
Can't wait seeing the next one.
Bye bye.