Holy moly!
Good job getting this far in the course.
You should really really
be proud of yourself
because we've learned a lot.
And now we're gonna build
something really exciting.
We're gonna build a startup landing page.
A landing page like this.
That well is responsive
but most importantly it has some text.
It has a button.
But check this out.
When you click on the button it takes you to a
form to sign up and collect email addresses.
That's right.
We're building a startup landing page.
I'm going to show you
how to do it step by step
and you can grab the starter
files attached to this lesson
because we're gonna build this from scratch
and see how we can put something online
that you can now share with your friends.
Next time you have a big
startup idea. Let's get started.