Welcome back.
So how are we going to
build this from scratch
based on what we've learned so far.
Well we're going to use Bootstrap
for this because we just learned it
and I actually gave you some starter files
attached to the last lesson.
If we take a look.
That's right.
We had a header image.
We had an "index.html" file
and then a "style.css" file.
So you can open these make sure
they're all in the same folder.
I called mine "startup" with an exclamation
mark because this is an exciting project
and in our case
we'll use Sublime Text.
We should have something like this.
So we have our "index.html" file
our "style.css" and then
our header image.
Now I filled in a few things
for you just to get us started.
Nothing too crazy though.
Don't worry.
One is we've used some
Google fonts so that we can
use this "Montserrat" font
which I think is kind of
nice from the Google fonts
and we enable that
in our style sheet by saying body and HTML.
I want to make sure that
the font family has this setting.
If not we'll use "sans-serif".
I've also set width and height for "100%".
That's always something
good to have to make sure
that the body and HTML cover
100 percent of whatever
we see on the screen.
Next we have our "Bootstrap CSS" from a
"CDN" or a "Content Delivery Network".
And the reason I've added this
here, is that so you don't have to
actually include a Bootstrap file yourself.
If I actually go to the Bootstrap page
and I go to "Quick Start"
you'll see that right here we can just copy
and paste this, just like here
with the Bootstrap CSS file.
So that way right away as soon
as we copy and paste this line
we have Bootstrap available to us.
Now notice here how we have
versions of Bootstrap.
In this case it's "4.3.1".
Now this number as the
time passes is going to get
bigger and bigger.
Because Bootstrap is a constantly
evolving library
as developers make updates.
But as long as you use
a number higher than this
everything in this
project should work.
Like I said most of the time no matter
when you're watching this video
as long as you copy this
or you use my starter files
everything should work.
And then finally we have our style sheet.
Nothing new here right.
Because we've already seen this before
we have our "style.css" file
and our style file just has
this for now.
We also have our header image which
again is a nice little laptop image
for our startup landing page.
Now this is the website over here that is
completely blank because we have nothing in the body.
So let's just have a "h1" that says
"Helllloooooo" right here.
Save it and refresh.
Look at that! We have
"Helllloooooo"
Now notice here how
fast I did that I just
pressed "Command+R" on
my laptop which is a Mac.
If you have Windows it's
"Ctrl+R" to refresh the web
page and you notice here
that the font is being
applied once again because
we have our font-family CSS set.
So there's our page,
our setup and there is what we
want to get to now if you
want you can go off on
your own and try to attempt to
built this from scratch yourself.
Otherwise I'll see you in the next video
to actually get our page to
look a little bit more like this
and less like this.
I'll see in the next one.
Bye bye.