All right.
Let's get going here now the first thing
we want to do is change this hello to.
Well the biggest startup event of the year.
Very dramatic.
I know.
So let's do that.
I'm just going to say the biggest
startup event of the year.
That's right.
OK.
Let's save.
So I'm doing "Command+S"
or if you're on Windows, "Ctrl+S"
and then refresh
"Command+R" or if you're on
windows "Ctrl+R".
All right.
There we go.
That's great.
We also seem to have a button
that says find out more.
So let's do that as well.
We'll say "button".
Find out more.
There we go.
If I refresh here.
There you go.
Our startup landing page is well
frankly still looking fairly ugly.
Now the next thing we want to do is
we want to have this background image.
But before we get to that
I want to talk a little bit about
how we can set up our HTML page
so that we have good responsive design.
So right now nothing much is going on.
You can see here that I
can adjust the screen size.
But we don't have much
happening on our page.
So if we go back to the
Bootstrap documentation
in the quick start guide if I
scroll all the way to the bottom
you see that I get a starter template here
and you might notice here something
that we haven't seen before
which is this part over here
called a "required meta tag"
and you can see here that this is actually
something that we can copy and paste
and place right below our title here.
Just like that.
Now let's make this a little
bit bigger so we can see
and I'll make the writing
smaller just so you
can see over here exactly what's happening.
So this meta tag allows us to
add new information to our HTML page
and there's different things that
we can provide.
Now in most websites you'll actually see these two
lines very often as a matter of fact it's recommended
that you always add.
Now what exactly do they do?
Well if we scroll down here you'll see
that we have the "responsive meta tag".
Essentially
this line here which says viewport
allows us to create web pages
that are developed mobile first.
That is we let the page
know or the browser know
that this page should work
on mobile devices and things
like scrolling or touching or zooming
on a mobile device is going
to work with this tag.
Now this is something I'm going to
leave for you to learn more about
and it's something we'll talk
about later in the course
but these meta tags are
just useful things to add
to our projects anytime
we create a new page.
And then finally this top meta tag
uses UTF-8 encoding essentially
it's saying hey we're going to use
this form of encoding to
write text on our pages.
Again something that if you're
curious you can read up on your own.
But now that we've set this up so
that it's good for mobile as well.
Let's try to include this
background image into our page.
Now when it comes to
background images on a website
that's a very common thing.
You'll see a lot of people adding
background images to a website
or maybe patterns or some sort of colors
and when a common problem
happens I always like well, Google
and one of the first things
that you'll encounter
is this perfect full page
background image by "CSS-TRICKS"
which we've seen before.
Now if you scroll all the way down
it tells us a way for us to make
sure that we use the image in a
full page background so that it stretches
it flexes as the view port changes.
Now over here it actually
gives us a copy and paste
way that we can use it ourselves.
So I'm going to just copy this
go to my style page and
just add this to our CSS.
Now you'll see over here that we're using
"background" over here with the "url".
So we want to adjust it to "header.jpg"
Because that's the url of the header.
And the key here is these lines.
It saying hey we don't
want to repeat the image
we want you to keep it centered
and we want you to keep it fixed.
And by using this line it stretches
or at least it fills the entire page
with our image and as long as we
have "background-size" as "cover".
Well let's see what happens.
I'm going to refresh.
Hey and look at that!
Now I have this image
that adapts to our page.
But the cool part is if I
open the developer tools here.
Let's say view developer tools you'll
notice that the image actually bumps up
so that the center of the
image well is always centered.
How cool is that!
So this is a very useful trick to
have your background very flexible.
All right.
So we have our background, hmmm!
Unfortunately our writing right now is
hard to see the button still kind of ugly.
So let's fix a few things in our HTML page.
Now remember we have Bootstrap so we
can start using some Bootstrap classes now.
One thing that I want to do is
with this "h1" tag I want to maybe use a
"strong" element to emphasize the header.
So make sure we close this and I'm gonna
make this bigger just so you can see.
And if I refresh.
All right that's emphasized
a little bit more.
We also want to make sure that
this "h1" tag we can actually see
So we can go into our style
and just create a new "h1" style that
will have a let's say a "font-size"
of let's say "3rem".
And then we'll give it a "color"
of, what should we do here?
Well one thing that I always like to do when
I'm trying to figure out what color I want
is to
go to a page let's say
like the startup over here
open up the developer tools
make sure this is a little
bit bigger so we can see
and then find somewhere on the page
where you have this color palette.
If I actually click on
this and I'm on Chrome
Look at that! It opens up a
little color palette for us
so I can actually move around things
and grab the hacks of
the color that I want.
In our case I want the color
to be well let's find out.
How can I copy the color of this page?
I can just click on select an element.
This little icon here.
And then if I hover over this look at that.
It shows me exactly what
color this element has.
You can see over here that
this is the hex color.
So I'm just going to copy that
come back and paste it in.
Now if I save both of these files
and refresh that's much better.
I like that a lot.
All right.
We're making progress with our page.
It's getting closer but
we still have a lot to do.
So let's take a break and I'll
see you in the next video.