All right everybody.
This is the exciting part!
Because up until now, well we've
created our startup landing page.
It looks great but it's
only on our laptops.
Right.
If you're starting a business you're
not going to go to every customer.
Give them your laptop and say "Hey
check out my startup landing page".
No we want to use the Internet right.
We want to be able to
put this website online.
But we also want people to
be able to click on this and
have a way to submit their email address
so that maybe when your startup
launches you can email them
and ask them to make a purchase.
So this is the fun part!
Now that we've created the page.
How can we make it interactive?
Well for this section we're going
to use something called MailChimp
and MailChimp is an
e-mail marketing service.
There's other tools like
MailerLite and a ton of others
that allow you to have
this exact functionality
a way for users to click on a
button, submit a form
and save that information
somewhere for you to use later.
Now in order for this part to work
we need to create an account and
sign up for free with MailChimp.
Now I've already gone through the steps
so you don't have to watch me type along
But just a heads up what we're
going to do it is completely free
isn't going to cost you anything.
But we do want to create
an account with MailChimp.
So that we can create our e-mail form.
So I want you to go ahead do this.
It might ask you for your home address
and that is actually a requirement
especially in some parts of
the world where to avoid
spam and spam bots.
You have to provide your home address
or some sort of an address so that
they know that you are a real human
who is asking people to
sign up to their newsletter.
But just go through the steps here.
Just create your password get started.
You might have to confirm
your account with your e-mail.
But it should take you no
longer than five minutes.
Once you have done that
you can pause the video.
Otherwise let's sign-in to MailChimp.
Now one thing actually before we
sign-in is if you look at the pricing
there is a free tier and this is where we're
going to use where we can just create a form.
And as long as we have less than 2000
contacts it's going to be completely free.
Again if you're creating a startup landing page and
you're getting more than 2000 people interested
well then you're probably going to make some
money so you can start paying for this service.
But up until 2000 sign ups,
well it's completely free.
So that's really really nice.
All right.
Once you've created an
account let's log in.
All right.
There we go.
We have our dashboard.
Now I want you to keep in mind when
you work with a service like this
which is essentially a
website online of a company
they're always going to
change how the website looks.
So when you're watching this video you
might not have the exact same look as I do.
Don't worry about it.
Most of the core functionalities
are going to be the same.
You might have just different
buttons organized differently.
But what we want to do is
essentially go to audience.
If you click on manage audience
click on sign up forms.
You can actually create your own audience.
So let's just call this one
"Zero to Mastery students".
You can have different settings such as
enabling captcha, enabling double opt-in
which again sends contact
opt-in confirmation.
So when people sign up they'll
get a confirmation e-mail
that they've subscribed and you
can also enable GDPR fields.
Now we don't need to
worry about that too much.
Let's create a form name named
call it "Zero to Mastery".
You can provide a default
e-mail address if you want.
Scroll all the way down.
And you don't need to worry about too much let's
just save audience and campaign defaults.
All right.
We've created our list.
So now if I click back on audience.
You see that I have "Zero
to Mastery students".
If I go to campaigns now
and say create campaign
and instead of a sign-up form we're
going to click on landing page.
Now the landing page name
can be whatever you want.
Let's say "Startup" with
an exclamation mark.
We want to target the audience
"Zero to Mastery students".
We can click begin
and here we can select
a template that we want.
Now in our case we can just
have the grow your list template
and you can customize
this however you want.
You can have different headings here such as
"This is the best business in the world!".
We can have a logo if you want.
We can use the Zero to Mastery
logo that I've already uploaded.
And we can just leave the email
and subscriber the way it is.
Again this website is going to let
you customize things differently
and depending on when you watch the video
these might be a little bit different.
It doesn't really matter as
long as we get this e-mail form.
So if I click save and close
and I go save and close.
We now have my startup page which I can just
add a page title let's say "Startup Idea".
We can add a URL.
So this allows you to have your
own custom URL if you want.
But in our case we want the free
option so I can just create let's say
"ztmstudents" and point so
if I save here.
I now have a page title, a URL, we have the
audience which is "Zero to Mastery students"
we have the content which is what we just created.
And all I need to do now is say publish.
High five!
Thank you very much. Now your landing
page is now live on the web right here.
So check this out if I copy and paste
this into the link there is my page.
Now all we need to do is copy this link.
Go to my find out more.
And make it so that when a user
clicks on it it goes to that page.
And that's super easy, right.
We can just create an
"a" tag with an "href".
And this "href" will have
the link that we just copied.
So let's close that
close the "a" tag.
If I hit save
and refresh if I click now.
How cool is that!
But this isn't even the coolest part.
The coolest part is now I can
create just a random e-mail.
Let's say "andy1234@gmail.com".
Click subscribe and oh
we have almost finished.
So you see over here how I got the
you need to confirm your email address
and that's because we clicked on that setting
where people had to confirm their email address
because well we don't want just
anybody to sign up to our newsletter
we want to make sure they're
human and not just bots.
So instead let's go back and
actually give my email address.
Subscribe
if I now go back to go to my email.
Hey check it out!
Look at that!
I have the "Zero to Mastery students".
Yes, subscribe me to the list.
So if I click on this now I'm
now subscribed to the list
and if I go to my campaigns.
You'll see that I have two
clicks on this campaign.
So if I now actually go to view report
I'll have a new subscriber
that if I go to audience now
you can see that I have a
new contact and there we go.
We have myself as the new subscriber.
And as people get more and
more interested in your startup
they're going to sign up more and more
and you'll be able to send them an email.
How cool is that!
Let's take a break and I'll
see you in the next video
so that we can actually put this website
online instead of just on our computers.
I'll see you on that one. Bye bye.