Welcome back.
I want to show you another easier way
to put your page online on GitHub.
That is fairly new.
All we need to do is
click on a new repository.
We can create whatever we want.
"startup-of-the-year"
we'll call it that for now.
We'll make sure it's public.
We can add a description if we want.
And we can initialize this
repository with a "README".
Now if I click Create repository
I now have an empty project
and all we need to do here
is click on upload files
and we can just drag and drop our files.
In my case I can just grab these
three files we've been working on.
Drag them over here.
It's going to upload them and
we'll just hit commit changes
and check it out once that's done
we have our page.
Now in order for this to work
we have to make sure that
there's an index.html file
and all we need to do is now go to Settings
scroll all the way down
to GitHub Pages right here
select the source as the master branch
and don't worry we're gonna go
over GitHub and how it works.
Later on the course we have
a dedicated section for it.
but I just want to make sure
that we can put things online
so you can show off to your friends.
If I scroll back to GitHub Pages now
you'll see that I have your site is
ready to be published right here.
So I can actually copy this link
or click on it and look at that.
At this URL my website is now online.
And as you can see it
works just like we had.
But this time it's an
actual website online.
So this link I can send to
my friends and show off.
Now one thing I like to do here when I
create a page on GitHub is to copy this link
go back to the project
and add it to the description
here as the website.
So that in the future
I can just click on here and
I'm directed to my website.
All right.
That was a lot of work but congratulations
you have your website online.
Go share with your friends with your
family with your dog with your enemies
and I'll see you in the
next video. Bye bye.