"What do I do if I don't have enough experience?"
"What if I'm underqualified for a job?"
Well, first of all, you should have this
mentality in mind when applying to jobs
and apply to jobs that you feel
you are under qualified for.
If a job is asking you to do something
that you already feel confident
then you should ask yourself "What
am I going to learn in this job?".
"Am I going to learn actually, is this job going to
put things on my resume that will make me get better
and get a better position in the future?
Or am I just going to do the same thing that
I already know what to do or how to do it?"
Finally, you have to keep in mind that job postings
are put in order to weed out the weak candidates.
I have seen way too many of these created by non-technical
people or just making job sound tougher than
it really is to remove junior
developers or engineers from applying.
So ask yourself:
"Is this job going to be tough?"
Good, then
that is what you want. That's
why you should be doing.
Do you feel competent?
You are very qualified for this job.
Ok then, maybe you should push yourself and apply
to a job that's more difficult than you think.
Every application should be a long shot. If you're applying
to something that you're 100 percent qualified for
where is your room to grow?
So dream big.
But in order to dream big,
you might have a bit of a roadblock.
What if you don't have enough experience?
See, I don't love resumes and I don't
think a lot of people do either.
But sometimes without a resume you cannot get an
interview. And in order to have a good resume
you need to have something to put on
it, like great experience.
Here's the catch though: "How can you have good
experience if you're just getting started?"
It's like you have no hope if you're a beginner or
if you don't have enough work experience because
you're just out of school
or you're changing careers.
Well not quite.
As with everything there's the
regular way of doing things
then there's the smart way.
You see experience doesn't come just
from working at another company.
There are many ways that you can
demonstrate experience without a past job.
And here you'll find my
favorite ways to show improve.
You can get the job done.
You won't have to do
every single one of them.
But two out of four of
these or even better
three out of four, will be great at showcasing
on your resume and make you stand up.
So let's go in order and
see how we can do this.
The first one is GitHub.
GitHub is a great way to demonstrate that you
actually code that you've built projects.
The number one thing you can do is to start making
commits and making sure that you have a good history
of things that you've done.
And by the way if you're wondering how I got this
cat picture in here I'll show you a little trick in
the next exercise to make your contribution
look a little bit nicer and busier.
In case you're just getting started and you don't
have a good past history. Another way to improve your
GitHub profile or to just add more experience is
contributing and participating in open source projects.
For example I've created a zero to mastery organization
where we have a ton of open source projects
by the community that you can contribute to and they're
made specifically for you to mess up, make mistakes.
Nobody is going to yell you.
These are just fun projects that are open source that
you can contribute to and you can do as much or as
little as you want but this will improve your
experience and contributing to open source projects and
it's something you can add to your resumes.
Now, contributing to open source projects
recruiters love seeing this because this demonstrates
you can work with others and also with something
like GitHub and version control.
All right let's look at the next one.
The next one is website.
If you are especially a full-stack or front-end
developer or even a designer you should have your own
website where you can showcase your skills.
This again is something you can speak about in your
interview and about how you built the website or it gives
you a good way to talk
about your past projects.
Now you're asking yourself: "Ah! Andrei, am I going to
have to build a whole new website and waste a bunch
of time?"
Well not really.
Let me show you a couple of tricks. You see you
don't need to build your own website from scratch.
There's a ton of free templates like creative tim
here that just gives you a nice template for you
to use and fill in with your information.
We can also look at this one.
And again free templates that you can use.
I especially like the mountain
template and you can see that, yeah!
I mean you can customize this to your own and make it
look professional and it's already designed nicely
and also customized for different experiences such
as mobile, tablet and in a day you can have your own
website.
And just to show you how you shouldn't really
spend too much time on your own website.
One of my favorite people
to follow is Kevin Kelly.
He is very very popular among the tech community
and he's just overall really smart thinker.
And you can see his website over here.
It's very simple.
Nothing exaggerated.
A very very clean but
small very basic layout.
And this is to show you that you
don't need some crazy animations.
Make it all flashy to stand out.
As long as you have a personal website
it just shows that you actually spend time building
it and doing something that most people wouldn't do.
Another thing that I want to show you is for example
the jobboard that we have for all of my students
and this is again another open source
project that the community built.
If we just search through let's say Toronto developers
here and we go to Christine Aqui I hope I'm
saying the last thing right.
You can see how simple yet
beautiful her portfolio is.
If we go to about me just a nice little bio with links
to her profile if we go to projects we see some
other projects.
And this is something that she can put on her
resume and immediately stand out from the crowd.
And it also gives her an opportunity to list projects
that she can talk about when she gets to an interview.
All right let's look at the next topic.
1 ~ 2 big projects. Now
you can't really fake experience. If you've never built
anything beyond a "to-do list" or a "Hello World" app
you simply will not be
able to get very good jobs.
However, most people think having a
hundred projects is the way to go.
So they do a project today and build small projects
many small tiny projects to have 30 of them and
they start building all these
projects that are very very simple.
Now that's not actually impressive.
I mean it shows that you're
working hard and coding along.
But if I'm a recruiter you can show me a project of
maybe "tic-tac-toe" but I don't really care that's
something that anybody can build with a
bit of coding experience in a day or two.
Frankly no recruiter or interviewer is going to
check out all your 30 projects. Most of the time
we want to hear your most
difficult or the hardest
biggest project you've worked on. Instead of
spending your time on these small little projects
spend your time on one or two big projects.
For example; in other course that I teach
we built a face recognition app.
And this app, well has a front end
using React.js, a backend where we have a RESTful API
server with Express. We've deployed it to Heroku.
We've created session management with authenticator
routes, we store user information such as username.
And also hashed passwords securely
in our database on Postgres.
We've deployed our app with Docker and we've also
used redis for session management and caching.
Now all of that may not mean a lot to you but having
something like a one big project they can talk
about all these things, will make you sound a lot
more impressive than somebody that just built a ton
of tiny projects. So focus on that have 1 to 2 big
projects that you can show off makes you stand out.
And it's also going to give you something to talk about
during the interview and put it up on your website
or create its own website and you immediately can
put this as the first item on your resume. Because
here's the thing; if you
don't have work experience
if we go back to the resume
we used in the exercise.
Remember this resume.
Well if you have no work experience, maybe for work
experience you can say something like javascript
developer or web application developer and
talk about how you build your project here.
Because to a recruiter it doesn't really matter if you
worked at a certain company building an application
or on your own or that could
be a little bit vague too.
They don't need to know that.
They just need to know that you build things that are
real that are big and complicated and you solved
hard problems.
So having one or two big projects they you can list
on your experiences, is a great way to add to your
resume if you don't have enough
past work experience at companies.
And I have a few students who have actually used this
technique to get interviews, even though they just
learn how to code
six months ago. And then finally
we have the blog posts or blog.
Let's have a look at what I mean by that.
This is another thing you can include in your resume,
especially if it's related to a technology you're
using or the company is using.
For example I have here my medium profile. medium.com
allows anybody around the world to just post
a blog post and it's very popular with the tech
community so there's a lot of tech related posts that
you right on medium and there's
other platforms like this.
What if you wrote a blog post about a specific
technology that the company you're applying for is using
or some sort of a technical problem that they're facing?
By doing that and just adding a link to that blog post.
It gives you again another
leg up to most people.
And the great thing about platforms like this is that
well if we go to one of my articles here you can
post it to what we call publishers and publishers
allow your post to be discovered by others.
And it's very simple to do.
You can write a blog post on medium in a day and submit
it to a place like hackernoon and lots of people
see it. And as soon as you show this to a recruiter
or an interviewer, again it automatically shows that
you know what you're talking about or at least it
makes you stand out from the rest. And you can do this
with YouTube videos as well.
But I prefer writing because it's a lot
faster and it looks a lot more professional.
So let's just review here; "what happens
if you don't have enough experience?"
Well all of these four points allow you to gain that
experience or show that you have experience without
actually having traditional
work experience.
All you need to do is start something on your own
and build something like a project or a portfolio
or a blog post.
This only shows initiative but you can focus
this project on solely getting your interviews.
Or you can participate in a hackathon or contribute
to open source projects. By taking this initiative
you're doing more than most people that hope to
just land an interview by sending a generic resume.
You'll immediately stand out from the crowd and
give you something to put on your resume that again
is different than the average developer.
Plus you have the added benefit of something
to talk about in your actual interview.
Remember nothing is given to you for free and luck
is for those who rather wait and go after what they
want so by simply building something
just for fun such as a side project.
You're showing how self-motivated
and ambitious you are.
Experience doesn't mean
on the job experience.
Write about your portfolio projects.
Maybe talk about your
website and how you built it.
Talk about your GitHub profile maybe a hackathon you
participate in and or open source projects you've
worked on.
Write a blog post on a specific technology that the
company you're applying to is using. All of them
answer this question:
"Do you have experience?"
Finally there are many things that you can add that are
not developer related, but can make you a great employee.
For example, "did you work
as an instructor at a camp?"
Well you can now add ability to manage
people and communicate well with others.
Any skill that is related to getting
the job done can be included.
Also if you have only had six months of coding
experience, don't show that on the resume.
That doesn't mean to lie but to hide that information.
Because a recruiter only glances at your resume.
They won't care if you're the best developer in
the world if they just see six months experience.
That's too risky for them.
Your resume will most likely be discarded
no matter how good of a developer you are.
So remember resumes are only good to get your foot
in the door. By tweaking your resume to show that
you have experience so that the recruiter thinks "Oh
interviewing this person is low risk because they
know what they're talking about",
is a good way of doing it.
"Do you have past experience?
Have you made good decisions in the past?
And have you worked on a challenging
problem and solve them?"
If you're able to answer yes to that
well then a recruiter is most likely
going to ask you for an interview.
I'll see you in the next video.