If there's one thing we have learned this entire time in this course is that there is nothing static
about being a web developer, improvements are constantly made all the time in ASML Success and JavaScript.
And even the browser's get constantly updated.
Libraries are also constantly being created.
If you remember, libraries are just pieces of code, they could be accessed, they could be HTML,
they could be JavaScript pieces of code written by somebody else so that we can use it so we don't have
to start from scratch.
Now it's human nature to want to constantly improve.
And in this video, we're going to learn the new features that everybody will be using.
But first, let's recap something from our previous videos.
If you remember, JavaScript was created by the Netscape browser and everybody else, all the other
browsers started using JavaScript, so Netscape submitted JavaScript to something called the FEMA International.
So that JavaScript could be standardized and they could say, hey, everybody use this version of JavaScript
on all browsers.
That's what ECMAScript.
Is ECMAScript is well, it's JavaScript, but it's just the standard way of calling it so that when
the browsers implement what JavaScript should do and how they read JavaScript, well, everybody agrees
on the standard.
Now, every time you see.
Something like this, like Essex, and you'll see that quite a lot.
Essex just stands for FEMA script.
So, yes, there was ECMAScript version one all the way through six, and we're currently it's version
seven, but it's still new.
So we're only learning version five and version six for now.
But version five and version six introduce some new features that are really, really powerful and make
coding in JavaScript really, really nice.
And most code bases that you'll see, we'll be using these features because they're very, very exciting
topic for me.
It's one of my favorite parts of JavaScript now, and I'm excited to show you some of these new features
that will make your life a whole lot easier.
Now, one thing you might be thinking, though, is, oh, Andre, I don't want to learn something if
browsers don't support them and I can't actually use them.
But don't worry, my friend, these are all features that are supported.
You know why?
Well, mainly because of something called Bable.
You see, a few years ago, Programer created Bable so that developers can start using new JavaScript
features as they come.
Remember, ECMAScript releases versions all the time now without having to wait for browsers to implement
these features, Bable allowed us to want to use them right away.
Now, how do they do that?
Let's have a look.
If I go in to try it out here.
You'll see that bable.
Shows me something I can write and we'll learn the syntax soon enough, don't worry, I can't write
something like this, which is the new way of writing JavaScript with ECMAScript six.
And it compiles.
Into this now, what does that mean?
It means that it reads a file line by line and then changes it to a version of JavaScript that all browsers
know, and it works on all browsers when we actually deploy our application or website, which means
putting it online after we're done with it, we can use Bable to say, hey, read our JavaScript file
and transform it into this so it works on all browsers.
So without even thinking about it, you can write all your code and the newest and best way of writing
it.
You can see how clean this is and BAPA will take care of changing everything for you so that browsers
can read it.
Isn't that awesome enough that let's learn some new syntaxes and don't be afraid?
Yes, five and six made JavaScript a whole lot easier and more fun to write from now on, will we take
what we learn in this video to write all our code?
Because it's what the industry is using right now, and this is why you will get asked during interviews.
So let's get started.
The first feature I'm going to show you is let and const.
These are actually very, very simple, these are new ways of declaring variables, so if you see over
here in our section online, you see that JavaScript Variables has now.
Two new ways of declaring a variable.
And as a matter of fact, variable that we've been using up to this point, we don't really need to
use it ever again.
We now have something called let to show you how both of these work.
Let's do a small example.
I'm going to say CONSED Player and Konstanz for constant.
We'll say, Bobby.
And we'll say let experience equals to one hundred and we'll say, let Wizzard.
Level equal to falls.
Now, if I do something like if.
Experience is greater than 90.
He calls the true.
OK, so these look like variables, nothing's different.
Let's run this through the council and see what happens.
OK, if I now check wizard level.
Fourth's, hmm, that's that's strange, right, because in the previous video where we talked about
the scope for had wizard level as a variable, I would have gotten through here.
So if this was variable and this was variable.
Wizard level, instead of being false, will be true.
Now.
That's confusing, right?
That's because it's not inside of a function.
This is a little bit tricky, but with variable, we only we're able to create a scope inside of a function,
but never if it had curly brackets.
But inside of if.
With LET.
When I say let and let.
Well, now I've created a wizard level variable inside of if so, the only way that I can access this
is inside the if if I do console dialogue wizard level here.
And console dialogue.
Wizard level outside and then let's put inside.
If I copy this.
I get true outside.
I get false because now with the lead, any time it's wrapped around a curly bracket, well, it creates
a new SCOP.
Versus with a variable, if I changes to a variable.
And I copy this again and refresh.
I get inside.
He calls the true and outside.
Equals to true, because wizard level has already been changed.
No new scope is created inside the curly brackets because this isn't a function.
Now, I know that's a really, really confusing, but the one big takeaway from this is just don't use
variable anymore.
Variable is actually quite confusing.
Now, think of that as the new variable.
So from now on, we're going to be using lot for variables.
But what is const?
Well, const is even cooler.
What's this?
If I want to change the experience level, I can say experience equals 80.
And now if I look at experience, well, experience equals 80, but if I want to change the player,
Bobby, to a new name.
He calls Sally.
I get an error assignment to constant variable, what that means is a constant you're not able to reassign
to the variable, so it cannot be updated.
Now, why would that be useful?
It's really, really useful because a lot of bugs happen when you're working in a team of people.
If you have something like a player and somebody changes the name of the player while you're working
on a program and you still think it's Bobbit and you keep getting errors because somebody else has touched
it.
Well, that's that's a bit of an issue, isn't it?
By using CONSED, you make sure that this player variable will always have the same value.
So this is actually very, very useful.
And my recommendation is that if you have anything that isn't going to change, it should be a constant.
So a function could be a constant because, well, if the function or if the assignment of A is not
going to change.
Then we feel a lot safer using CONSED than, let's say, LED, because we make sure that nobody assigns
something else to a.
So the rule from now on is use courts, if you're using a variable that doesn't change, most of the
time you'll use this.
And if you're using a variable that you assign something to like wizard level where it changes from
true to false.
False, true.
Well, then use let.
One thing with Consed that you have to keep in mind is that if you do, a const object equals.
Bobby experience one hundred and Wizzard level.
To false.
Well, if I copy this object.
And try to reassign this object to, let's say, a number.
I get an error because it's a constant, but if I try and change a property.
My wizard level is the true.
So one thing with consent is you can change the properties of the objects still you just can't reassign.
All right, onto more fun things.
Let's do the structuring and these ones that I'm going to show you are going to make your life a whole
lot easier.
Again, if we actually have our.
Object here, let's say that we wanted to grab these objects, so we'll have to do consed player equals
object player.
We'll do concerts, experience equals object dot experience and then let wizard level equals object
dot wizard level.
And that was a whole lot of typing to access these properties, well, with the structuring, you can
do this, you can say.
Player and experience.
So with this syntax.
It does the exact same thing as the first two lines over here, you just select the properties you want
from an object and now you have CONSED player and experience available to you so you can use player
anywhere you want in your code base and then forget we can do wizard level equals.
Much, much cleaner.
You just have to get used to it, but it's a lot nicer to look at.
All right, another thing, cool thing you can do with objects consed name equals John Snow.
We can just start a new.
Object here, and we can say now name.
Hello, and we can do Ray.
Smith High.
All right, so this is a silly object, but I wanted to show you some new ways of declaring object properties.
Now, in Essex, you can have instead of the old way of having just player or experience or wizard level,
we can have something dynamic that we can assign like John Snow, or we can do Ray plus Smith, or we
can do one plus two and have these dynamic property values.
Let me show you how they work.
If I access the object now, I have three equals high high and John Snow equals hello again, new ways
of declaring properties very useful if you need to calculate something for the property value.
But even cooler is being able to do something like this.
Imagine you had a cast a equals to Simon.
Can't equals to true.
And C is an empty object.
And if we wanted to add these to an object, we would have had to do A as A, B is B and C is C.
And sometimes you wanted the property to match the value again with the new JavaScript, if property
and value are the same, in that case, we can just say A, B, C, so we can remove we can remove the
declaration that we had with property and value if they're the same and just keep it like this.
Again, this is something that when we get to the Rijad section, it's going to become very, very useful.
All right, something even more fun, and this time it's template strengths, so template strengths.
Now, remember, when we have, let's say, a greeting, how knowing it was that we had to do hello?
Name plus, you seem to be doing.
Greeting and then let's say you had an exclamation mark and you also had to worry about backlash if
you had an apostrophe that was really tedious and annoying.
Now, you knew something really fun instead of doing it this way.
You can have greeting that equals something called template strings, and these are back sticks, so
the fact that this is right above your Tabqa, if you're on a Mac instead of using double quotes or
single quotes.
This means Templestowe drinks and now you can use double quotes or single quotes anywhere you want and
will be a string, but even cooler if you have name equals.
Sally and age equals 30 for pet is horse.
Now we can do hello.
Name.
You seem to be noticed the syntax and the coloring page, minus 10.
What a lovely.
Pat, you have.
So notice what we did here and I'm going to copy this just so we have it.
I'm going to comment this out now, if I look into the console, I'll refresh.
You see that now, instead of doing all that double quotes and plots and worrying about spacing within
these back decks, I can say a piece of string and then add dynamically by using the dollar sign, then
the curly brackets, a value that we want.
We can again do any sort of expression, so age minus 10.
What a lovely pair you have.
Let's see what happens if I do greeting best.
Look at that, hello, Sally.
You seem to be twenty four.
What a lovely horse you have.
Very cool.
So this is very, very useful.
We'll be definitely using this later on in the course.
Another thing I want to show you is default arguments.
I can do something like Great will say name equals.
Empty string.
Age equals 30 and we'll say, Pat.
Is cat, let's just copy what we had before.
With the greeting.
I'm going to comment this out.
And we'll return this so nothing's changed.
We just have a function that returns a greeting.
The only thing that's new is this.
Let me show you what it does.
If I comment this out, I copy this, put it into the console, and now I run Grete.
Hello.
You seem to be 20.
What a lovely cat you have.
Dickerson, even though our browser and let me just refresh, you know for sure that our browser has
no idea of what age or Pett is, but if I run this function.
Because of the way I made the parameters, I gave them default arguments, which says if I don't provide
a value for name, which I haven't, I haven't given any arguments.
Well, then make name empty shrink, make age 30 and make pet cat.
If I do now greet John 50 and we'll do monkey, now I get Hello John, you seem to be 40.
What a lovely monkey.
You have this.
Gets ignored because I've passed it parameters, but otherwise I can pass a default parameter so that
when somebody calls this function and they don't provide these arguments.
My function won't fail because, well, I have default arguments.
Very cool.
All right, what else do we have?
Let's refresh your.
If you remember, we had one more type to do, JavaScript types, and that is a symbol, it's actually
not used very often, but I wanted to show you just because well, it's a typo.
We want to complete the seven types of JavaScript.
And a symbol.
Is special because.
Five, Simbel one, I create a symbol by doing this index, and I could have a second symbol that is
symbol.
And within here, we can put anything we can put through.
And variable.
Symbol three equals symbol, and we'll say FU as well, what's so unique about symbols and we should
be using Polet here.
If I copy this.
And I access someone I get Simbel access to, I get food and SIM three, I get food.
But the unique thing is that if I do seem to equals same three.
I get false, even though, well, they look like they're the exact same thing and symbols are used
because they create these completely unique type so that you can make sure there's never going to be
any conflict.
And the symbol value is used as an indent fire, mostly for object properties.
It's pretty much the only purpose of that because sometimes you don't want object properties if you
have thousands of them to collide and be the same ones, because then you'll get bugs.
We won't see too much in the course.
You won't see it out in the wild too much.
But I wanted to show you it regardless because, well, we want to know all the JavaScript types.
All right, one last one, I know we've covered a lot, but this is the best one, and that is Arrow
functions.
Up to this point, if we wanted to do something like add, we had to do a B.
And we turn A plus B and you might have gotten sick and tired of constantly writing function over and
over and over.
Well, now you have our functions, so within our function, you can do.
So any time you see this syntax and I had to pass and be here as well, any time you see this syntax,
it's the same thing as saying function.
But now it is just the shorthand form so that you don't have to constantly write function.
And the beauty of it is that you could have done return.
And B, and that completely works, so the only difference is that we have a function expression that
accepts a parameter and we have this fat arrow.
But with an error function, if you have a single return.
You can just put it on one line and it assumes that you want to return this if I save this.
And copy it in here.
Oh, I don't need the syntax.
Let's copy that one more time.
Add four and two.
That's the first function and then the new way with the error function, add to.
Again, I get the same thing.
It returns automatically because everything well, it's on one line.
It looks very, very nice, a lot easier to write than the above.
And there you have it, I know that was a lot of information, make sure you do the exercises after
this video to get yourself familiar with the syntax is just new ways of doing things.
These are going to help you to write better, cleaner code.
And just to show you what we've covered.
Well.
You've managed to finish everything in the section outline from variables to conditionals to finally
the error function, we've covered everything that we've wanted to do for JavaScript and moving forward,
we're going to be using these new syntaxes to write our code.
I hope you're excited as I am to start using these, I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.