Welcome back.
Now, what you'll learn in the next few videos is quite advanced, it does take some time to really
grasp the concepts and understand them, and the best way to do that is to do these yourselves.
So use these videos as a reference to come back to when you have questions.
I'm going to cover the main topics that you'll see out in the wild.
You can come back and reference these videos whenever you have questions.
And in this video, we're going to tackle advanced functions.
Now, I have a sample function for you here, but knowing what we learned about the new JavaScript syntax,
we're going to convert this first to how we should write JavaScript function.
Word is gone now.
We can just say.
Consed first equals.
And this error function has a greet, which can be a constant and a function.
Which again, can be consed second.
And finally, this.
Can be a concert as well.
We also learned about SCOP, an important property of function.
Is that the variables created inside of them?
Including the parameters are local to the function.
So that means that every time we run the first function, this block of code gets executed and the great
variable gets created every time.
Now, this is actually good for us because we make sure that if our program, every time we run first
remember to greet, well, it will have conflicts because it's a constant and we constantly reassign
the same thing to a variable that already exists.
So this way, within a function, we make sure that every time we run it, it's a clean slate.
You can name the variables however you like because there's nothing else that will collide with it.
Like I said, this behavior helps prevent accidental interferences between functions and as developers,
we want to minimize the number of bugs or errors in our code.
If all variables were shared by the whole program, it'd take a lot of effort to make sure no name is
ever used for two different purposes.
Imagine if grit was in another function and we had no idea and we can't use it.
Well, luckily, by having our own separate scope, we're able to make sure that we can use without
having to check the entire code base.
Now, by treating function local variables as existing alling within the function, the language makes
it possible to read and understand functions as small universes where whatever happens in that universe
only matters to itself.
But I also wanted to demonstrate an interesting concept with JavaScript, and that is closure's you
can think of it as this a function runs the function executed.
Now, it's never going to execute again.
Kind of like the first function.
We just executed it here and the result we put into new function.
It's going to remember that there are references to those variables alive in a memory first, however,
we see a problem here.
You see that when we load up this program on our website, the JavaScript engine will see this, I'll
say, OK, we have a variable first.
That's a function.
Great.
And then in the next line, we see, oh, we want to assign variable new function and we want to get
the result of first.
So the program runs first sees that we want to create a constant great high.
And then we also see that we have another function called second and we're returning that function.
But there is a problem here rate.
Second, we need to remember what greed is, although first.
Runs and returns second.
So you can think of this as once we do this, we will only have the second function.
Now, and I know this is this looks confusing, but just look at the highlighted here, that's what
calling first means.
But you see over here that the great variable second doesn't.
Well, it's not within the scope of second rate.
What closure's does, and this is a rule in JavaScript is that the child SCOP always has access to the
parent scope.
So it's almost as if it remembers.
They always remember that there's a reference to those variables a lot.
So inside the Web browser, the Web browser says, oh, this second function needs grid.
So I'm going to remember it.
Let me demonstrate that for you.
So if I do first here.
And I'm going to copy this into the console.
And now we have new function if I run new function.
I get high, even though first is never going to be Iran again.
The only thing that we have left is the second function, the Web browser remembers Grete.
Again, this is a confusing concept when you hear for the first time, but like I said, just remember
closure's.
Is just saying a function ran the function.
Executed.
It's never going to execute again.
But it's going to remember that there are references to those variables, so the child SCOP.
Always has access to the parents.
Now, you may be wondering if I did hear Consed name equals Bobby.
Will the first function have access to Bobby?
No, it wouldn't.
So think of it this way children always have access to their parents cope.
But parents go.
They don't have access to their children.
All right, let's get into a few more things.
Next, we're going to talk about currying.
And recurring is the process of converting a function that takes multiple arguments into a function
that takes them one at a time.
Let's see what I mean.
We have a function here.
We'll call it multiply and multiply.
It sets.
Two parameters.
And again, we're using our new functions, index will say A multiplies B.
Now, currying means we're changing this function to only accept one parameter at a time, so that means
we do.
Curried multiply.
Equals.
A, b.
A times B.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, what did we just do?
And again, this looks very confusing, but think of these arrows as functions.
So right now, if I do curried.
Multiply and I'll just say three, but let's see this in action, what happens?
I get a function that accepts be multiplied by.
So by running, this is saying that A is three.
And now we'll know that when you multiply a history, but because this has a function and another function,
so a function inside of a function, this just returns this part.
So it returns a function.
As you can see here.
So now, in order to make this work, let me put this back.
In order to make it work, we have to say curried.
Multiply.
We'll say three and then another bracket for.
If we look at this function compared to here, we see exactly what we did, we created a variable courage
multiplier that accepts a parameter.
So it's a function that accepts a in this case, it's three.
And once you call that function, once you've run it, it returns another function that accepts B and
that function multiplies A and B..
So what I'm doing here is saying create a multiplier.
A is three.
B is four and now multiply A times B.
And as you can see, as I said about couriering, it's the process of converting a function that takes
multiple arguments, like I said, into a function that takes them one at a time.
Now, why do we even need to do this, because now it's more extensive.
All I can do something like multiply by five equals.
And now I have this, so any time I want to multiply by five, I could just say, let me copy this.
Now, any time I want to multiply a number by five.
And now I have this function that was created that always multiply things by five.
Which is very cool.
All right, we're going to get into one more thing, and then I promise I'll make your head stop hurting.
It's called Campo's.
And Campo's is the act of putting two functions together to form a third function where the output of
one function is the input of the other.
Even me saying that, I'm like, what did I just say?
So let's write this down a compose.
Let's say f Anji parameters EFG return a function.
That takes parameter A. That returns a function that has.
This.
Holy moly.
And if you look at this and you have no idea what's going on, this is something that takes years for
some to get.
It is really, really advanced stuff.
But if you're able to understand the inner workings of this, you can pretty much do anything.
Let's let's give it a go.
What is happening here?
Well.
It looks like looking at F and G, it looks like F is a function because while we have the brackets,
it even highlighted in blue for you and G is also a function.
If I had a sum function that that, let's say, takes a number.
What we can do with Campos is I can say compose again, we have the function here some some so both
F and G are some.
And now, because it takes another bracket, I can say.
All right, so let's run this and then we can go step by step to show you what it does.
I get seven, so why is that?
Well, let's take it one by one.
If both F and G are some and A is five.
We look at what the function returns and because, again, we have two brackets, we're executing the
first part of the function which returns us another function, which is this.
And within it we give the A five.
So when this function runs, it says A is five.
OK, and then let's run the inner function G in this case, it's some.
So if you remember some is just saying give me five and then five plus one.
So now this changes to six.
And then finally the F function runs, which is again some and this says some is giving me six.
So six plus one.
Is seven.
And this whole thing returns seven.
Well, all right, that was a whole ton of stuff, but I want you to remember these three key words,
because when you get to advanced JavaScript functions are really, really important.
You'll hear words like closure's encouraging and compose a lot and you'll find tools and libraries that
use these heavily.
Now, you don't need to know the definition of them.
You just need to be able to read a piece of code and understand what's going on.
And this is why I like showing you this, although it's really advanced and very hard to to grasp by
understanding the step by step process of how a function works.
This is really useful because now when you encounter this in the wild, you'll understand how everything
works.
Now, to finish off this function section, I want to tell you the most important thing that you can
do as a web developer when creating code.
And that is the idea of avoiding side effects.
And functional purity.
What does that mean?
Well, let's go back to my diagram here.
You might remember this from the first part where we said a input is what we give, a function input
of some sort.
It could be an empty input or it could have parameters like five or ten.
A function does something that we define.
It has its own scope.
But remember, it's its own universe.
It could have a log, it could do a bunch of stuff.
And then it asks, am I returning anything you can?
This should be undefined.
So you can return a value or if it doesn't return anything, it just does on define.
Now, the two wars that I just said, side effects and functional purity.
Well, side effects are any of these things, any of actions that happen.
Inside of the function that we don't really know anything about, if it interacts or reads or writes
to an external variable, for example, or console logs, well, that's a side effect.
If we change here, a variable one equals one.
And then I have a function.
That changes a.
Well, that's a side effect, that's something that the functions doing to affect the outside world.
Remember, we want to think of functions as its own universe.
And if it starts affecting the outside world, I mean, it's not the end of the world.
We've done console long before we've done.
We've done this before.
But it is good practice to avoid these side effect.
And by avoiding these side effects, we have something called functional purity and functional purity.
Is a concept where we say in order for us to write really, really good programs, we want to avoid.
And we always wonder.
So that this and this are gone.
And we always return something.
And what's the power in this?
By avoiding side effects.
And always returning, we create something that we call deterministic and deterministic is a word that
you may have heard, it means that no matter what if my inputs, let's say five and 10, go through
this function, this little universe, the return value will be always the same.
Let me say that again, the input, whatever we put in the parameters, whether it's empty or it has
certain parameters, it always returns.
If we run this a thousand times, it always returns the same value.
That's determinism, it's a very important concept, and that's a key principle in avoiding bugs, because
if this function always does the same thing, well, then you know exactly what it does and you won't
have random errors popping out here and there.
That's what I want to leave you with.
Although this is not the law and you'll find code bases that will have a lot of side effects, there's
going to be a lot of things happening inside functions that maybe even affect variables that live outside
of a function.
It is really, really good practice to be a top performing developer, to have this in mind of creating
functions that minimize side effects.
And have functional purity, what we call determinism, where anything you put into the function, it
always returns the same thing.
All right, that's it for now, go try out some exercises.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.