Welcome back.
We're going to talk about some advanced 'objects' concepts.
Now, as I said, with both arrays and functions, these are advanced concepts, you're probably not going to
just get it a 100 percent the first time around, but use these videos as a reference to come back as you
progress through your career.
Now in this video, I'm going to talk about three things that are important with objects.
We're going to talk about 'reference type'.
We're going to talk about 'context'.
And finally we're going to talk about 'instantiation'.
So let's get started with the first line. 'reference type'. What I mean when I say a 'reference type'?
Well, I wanted to see if I can guess what's going to happen when I do array'[]' equals array'[]'.
What do you think the answer is going to be?
Let's see.
Hmm! interesting.
OK, what if I do array one equals array one? interesting.
OK one more question.
What about something like this?
'Object1'
equals the value of 10,
and we'll say 'object2' equals 'object1'.
And we'll finally say a variable(var) 'object3' equals value 10.
So looking at these and I'm actually going to copy it on here, so you can see it as well.
Looking at this,
What happens if I do 'object1' equals 'object2'?
What do you think will happen?
True.
OK.
That makes sense, I mean 'object2' is 'object1'.
But what if I do 'object1' equals 'object3'.
Here I get, false.
But why is that? We have value 10, value 10.
They're both the same thing.
Right.
Let's check something else.
What if I do 'object1.value'
equals 15, OK.
And now I do 'object2.value'
it equals 15.
But if I do 'object3.value', I get 10. Well that was confusing right.
Let's look at what's actually going on.
And this is the first topic we're talking about which is 'reference type'.
Let's look at a diagram.
Objects are what's called the 'reference types' in Javascript.
Up untill this point, all the other javascript types that we've learned including 'numbers', 'null', we have
'undefined', 'booleans', 'strings' even 'symbols' they're all defined by the programming language.
So Javascript, the person who wrote javascript and ECMAScript the standard says these are primitive types.
We tell you what they are. Now a 'reference type' which is a non primitive type are not defined by the
programming languages.
What that means is that they're created by the programmer.
So let's look over here as an example.
When I say variable.
Number one equals one.
Javascript knows what one is.
It's a number.
It's a primitive type.
It's always the same thing.
It's immutable every time it uses the one that's the same one that javascript knows about.
When I do variable number two, yah it's using the same number one that javascript knows about.
However when we created 'object1' equals 'value 10' and 'object2' equals 'object1' and 'object3' equals
the 'value 10', well those are created by the programmer.
There are 'reference types'.
So what we said was I want 'object1' create a new object, will say this box over here this filing cabinet
and in it, put 'value 10' into this box. 'object2' says, I want you to just reference and that's where the
word comes from,
reference 'object1', saying hey! I want whatever's inside this box. When 'object3' gets created,
it's a new object because we have the new brackets.
And it's saying put 'value 10' in this box.
Essentially what we're doing is saying, when we create a variable(var) 'object1' when we're storing just a reference
an address to where we're storing the 'value 10' which is 'Box1'.
So we're saying 'object1',
I'm just letting you know that this is the address of all the contents that you want
and that's  in 'Box1'. 'object2' is saying, I want whatever is an 'object1'
and we look an 'object1', an 'object1' just has the information of 'box1'.
So it references that, an 'object3' creates a new object.
So it's saying, I'm going to put my contents in 'Box3' and I'm just going to have the address of the box
saying 'Box3' that's right over here.
So going back to our example,
this makes sense, when we change 'object1' value to 15,
we change the contents of 'Box1'.
So when we do 'object2.value' which is referencing the same box as 'object1' that's 15,
but 'object3.value' doesn't change because that's, that's interested in a completely different box, it's 'Box3'
and going back to the first example.
Arrays, well as I mentioned in previous videos, arrays are just objects at the end of the day.
So when you create an array, it's the same thing, creating a box, a data structure.
And this is creating a second data structure.
Right.
So that is a 'reference type'. A very important concept but I think, I think you get it right.
Let's get to the next one.
This gets a little trickier.
This one's called 'context' and 'context' gets confused a lot with 'scope'.
If you remember, we said that 'scope' is created when it sees curly brackets, right!.
We said that, if we create a function, as soon as we create that function
there is a new 'scope' that's created.
So we can have, 'let a' equals 'a' and that lives within this universe.
It doesn't know anything about the root scope which is over here.
So if I do 'console.log(a)', well it's not going to work.
Oh! and we need to actually assign something and we need to name it to let's just say 'b'.
So if I do this, well 'console.log(a)'.
well, just return 'ReferenceError' because it doesn't exist.
So that's 'scope'.
Now how is 'context' different? 'context' tells you, where we are within the object.
Let me explain.
If, we say 'console.log(this)'.
Well you see, I get some highlighting, and this is the first time we're seeing 'this',
and it's a special word in javascript.
Probably the most confusing word that a lot of people have trouble and even people that I've been in
the industry for years still have a difficult time with 'this'. But let's see what it is.
'this' is, as you can see, the 'window object'.
So just to double check, if I do 'console.log(this)' equals 'window', I get true.
And I can access 'this.alert("hello")'
So what 'this' means, is what is the object environment that we're in right now, the best way to think about it is,
what is to the left of the dot?
So right now, I'm able to do 'alert' because I'm inside the 'window object'.
So doing 'window' or doing 'this' is the same thing.
Now why is that important?
Well when we get to 'instantiation', I'll show you why it is? but it's a very important concept
that you'll see again and again.
But remember, 'this' just refers to what object it's inside of. Two more example to demonstrate 'this'.
One is, if I do 'function a()', withem function 'a',
will say 'console.log(this)'.
So if I call 'a', what do you think happens?
Let's see. still the window object 'this'
still refers to the function.
And if you remember that's because I said, it has to be what object we're inside of right now.
Technically function 'a'.
I can go 'window.a' and run the function.
So to the left of the dot, well that's the 'window', in order to create a new value for 'this'.
You have to do something like this.
'object', 'a' function 'a'.
Now if I do 'function()'
and within here I do a 'console.log(this)'.
Well, in that case, if I copy this and run 'object4.a'
Well,
Now this is the object, which is 'object4'.
So why is that important to us?
Well, first of all you'll see it in other codebases, so it's good to know.
But it's really important when we do 'instantiation', 'instantiation' is when you make a copy of an object
and reuse the code.
Imagine you're building a big multiplayer game online, and this game is going to have many many players
you can have wizards you can have trolls, warlocks, elves.
Now, if you had to create an object for every single player that's a lot of repeated code,
that's a lot of hassle and well, that's a lot of your time and it's not very efficient.
To solve that, you can do something called 'instantiation'.
You're making instances or multiple copies of an object.
So let me show you how we do 'instantiation' in javascript.
Again this is going to look, a little bit weird at first, just like 'for' loops did, just like 'functions' did
at the beginning, but it's just the syntax, and you'll get used to it.
So let's say we have a 'Player' 'class'.
Now you see the new syntax already, and I capitalize a 'class'.
Now, think of a 'class' as something that I want to make a copy of.
If I ever want to make a copy of an 'object', it's a good idea to do something like this, so that well, you'll
see how easy it is to copy this now.
So we do.
'class Player'.
And within here, will say 'constructor'
and I know this looks weird but again it's just syntax.
Let's give it, this 'Player' can have a 'name' and a 'type' and within the constructor 'this.name' equals
'name' and 'this.type' equals 'type'.
Oh boy! What just happened here.
'constructor', when you create a 'class', a 'Player', 'class' says.
Every time I'm making a copy of a 'Player' the first thing that gets run is the 'constructor' function and
this 'constructor' function is gonna create these properties on the 'Player' object.
So 'name' and a 'type'.
And now I can create anything that I want for the 'Player'.
Let's say, we want to create a method such as 'introduce()' that 'console.log(s)'
with back ticks(`), 'Hi I am' and again if you remember this syntax template strings,
'this.name', 'I'm a', 'this.type'. Awesome!
So, now I'm saying, this 'Player' class, any player that I create will always be able to introduce himself and
they'll also have 'this' 'name' and 'this.type'.
And the reason we use 'this' here is that when we create a 'Player' we can access the name and type property.
I'll show you later on how that works.
But this is just the syntax you're going to get used to. In order to access
the 'Player' and make copies of it.
You'll have to run a 'constructor' which is all the properties and methods
that you want the 'Player' to have.
You can also create methods that 'Players' can have and any time you want to access a property
within the 'constructor' well use 'this.name' for (if I) wanna use 'introduce' I'll have to do 'this.introduce'.
OK, so we have a 'Player' but when we're building our multiplayer game
we want to now copy this but add onto it.
Let's say we have what we want to create a wizard player, a player that's a wizard.
In that case, we would do,
'class Wizard' again capital letter
'extends' and again is just the javascript keyword 'Player'.
So what is this saying?
I'm saying, I want 'wizard' to extend whatever 'Player' has.
So I want to add on top of whatever 'Player' has, again because it's a 'class', I have to do a 'constructor'.
And this 'Wizard' is going to accept 'name' and 'type' and within here, this is the tricky part.
Any time we extend something we need to also call the 'constructor' function of the 'Player'.
We have to do something called 'super' with the properties that we want to pass to the 'constructor'.
In this case, 'name' and 'type', I know this is confusing, is just something you have to do,
whenever you 'extend' a class,
you want to use super's so that you essentially have access to these.
OK, so let's say that with the wizard, we also want to have a 'play' function.
And the 'play' function was just a 'console.log'.
'WEEEEEE I'm a', 'this' 'type' and now that we have our wizard, what's the power?
what's the reason that we just did this?
Now we can do this, instead of constantly creating 'Players' and then saying that they have their Wizards
and they can play.
Now I can say 'wizard1' equals 'new' 'Wizard' and we'll call the first wizard again.
We get 'name' and 'type'.
So we'll say 'Shelly' and she'll be a 'Healer'.
And if I want to create a new wizard, I'll just say 'wizard2' equals 'new' 'Wizard' 'Shawn' and he is 'Dark Magic'.
Ooh!, There was a lots of new syntax, so let's go through it and make sure we understand everything.
As we've learned, let's use console log(console.log) to really understand what we're doing.
I'm going to add a console log(console.log) right of the top over here.
And will say 'this'.
What is 'this'.
I'm going to save, and actually I'm going to copy this into the console.
Let's copy it.
And see what the console log gives us?
We see that we get 'Wizard'.
All right, let's go through everything here.
I say, we have a 'class Player' then a 'class Wizard' that extends 'Player'.
And then we have two variables that we created 'wizard1' and 'Wizard2'.
Now the program's going to see the 'new' keyword and any time it sees a 'new' keyword it says, oh! we're
creating a new 'Wizard' and this 'Wizard' is going to have two parameters 'Shelly' and 'Healer'.
So it's going to go to the 'Wizard' class again because it has this 'new' word.
He goes to the 'Wizard' class and it says, hey! 'Wizard' I want you to extend 'Player'.
So it's going to go to the 'constructor', and it's gonna see this 'super' and what this does, is it takes
us up to the 'constructor' of the 'Player'.
And it runs this, and now it attaches 'this' as the 'Wizard' and then it introduces the 'new' function and then
adds the 'play' function.
Now, if I go to 'wizard1' and I say 'play', I get 'WEEEEEEE I'm a healer', because Shelly is a healer.
But I also have access to 'wizard1.introduce', 'Hi I am Shelly, I'm a healer'.
And, we also have access to 'wizard2', Uh! I have to run this again.
Let's run this again.
And I don't think I copied the second 'wizard' last time.
So now I have 'wizard2. introduce'.
'Hi I'm Sean',
'I'm a dark magic'.
That sentence doesn't make sense Sean but that's OK for now.
Let's just try something.
If I do 'console log'
here.
And we'll just say 'wizard'
and here will say 'player', just so we can distinguish between them.
And I'm only going to copy the first wizard so that we don't get two of these running, again because
we're creating two 'wizards', we're going to have this run twice. But just for our sanity, we'll run.
'Shelly'. So I'm going to refresh and add here. Ooh!I forgot to add a comma
and let's refresh, and I get an error, 'Reference Error',
'Must call super constructor and derived class before accessing 'this''.
What that's saying is, that in order for me to access 'this' and get 'this.type', I have to call 'super' which
runs a 'constructor' function and 'player'.
So that's what 'super' is doing.
It sounds kind of weird but it just something that you need. I'm gonna just put this at the bottom after we call
'super' and now it should work.
Let's see
I get, the first 'player' 'wizard'.
So we call 'super' as soon as we say 'new wizard', 'Shelly, Healer'.
I go to the 'wizard' extends 'Player',  I run the 'constructor' function which says 'super', hey! run the
'constructor' function and the 'player' and I run that.
And that's why we log 'console log player' first and then we go to 'console.log' 'wizard' and then run
the rest of the class.
Very cool!.
Now just to show you something.
This is actually new syntax that you'll see and 'react' and it was part of ES6.
But back in the day, this is how we used to do it. The exact same code I have up there
is right here it's called classical inheritance and it doesn't look too too bad but you see that there's
prototype which it's another thing that you'll see in javascript and to be honest with you,
you shouldn't really use it.
It doesn't look very nice and you see that we have to attach 'play' to both 'wizard1' and 'wizard2' and
it just doesn't look as nice as this.
And once you get used to everything.
It's not too bad.
All we're saying is, as soon as we say 'class', we say,
hey! we're probably going to make a copy of this object.
So we want to make copies of player, we want to make copies of 'wizard' and that's called 'instantiation'.
When I do the 'new' keyword, I say make an instance of 'wizard' and 'wizard' uses some functionality from
the player and adds its own little 'play' function as well.
Holy moly, that was a lot, like I said, this is something that you'll have to come back to and you won't
get it right away.
It's really really hard to fully understand the topic without actually having to use it in real life.
Just keep this in mind, every time you hear somebody talk about 'reference type' or 'context' or even 'scope'
or 'instantiating' something.
Well, these are the things that they're talking about.
'Objects' are really really complicated.
They're really hard.
But with that, it gives us a lot of power.
So with that, good luck with the exercises, I'll see you in the next one. Buh-bye.