So in the past, the way we would solve this is we would do an if statement, right?
So let me just remove myself from now and in here.
I'm also going to minimize this.
So is just Andre Pokémon object.
And in here, instead of doing what we've done here, we would do if and say, Andre Pokémon, DOT Pikachu
and if Andre Pokemon dot.
Pikachu Dot, wait, let's make this a little bit smaller so we can see.
Then.
We want to.
Create weight to the variable.
Otherwise.
Way to equals undefined, so by doing this, we won't get that error so we can check to see if Andre
has Pikachu.
So if I copy this over, let me just remove this from now.
If I copy this over, hit enter, I get no errors.
And if I add console logs in here.
Run this again.
You see that I get on to find because, well, it will realize that Andre Pokémon Object doesn't contain
Pikachu, so this is actually pretty annoying to do.
And you'll see often code bases have something like this and then do Andre Pokemon and they keep checking.
Does this exist?
Does this object exist?
So on and so forth.
So the cool thing about optional chaining is that, well, it avoids this complication.
So I can change this to say, let's wait three.
Equal Andre Pokémon.
I can say, is there an object and then do Pikachu?
Is there an object or a property of Andre Pokemon that is Pikachu and then do dot wait.
So by doing this, check this out.
If I do console log wait and I copy this.
I get the same thing, I get undefined because it checks all of these and eventually because Pikachu
cannot be found in this object, it's going to assign undefined to wait three without throwing any errors.
But if I did have Pikachu.
And I tried this again.
You'll see that I get 30, so everything is working, so instead of having those long if statements,
I can just check for properties with this question mark.
Very, very cool.
Now, this video's getting long, so let's take a pause and then we're going to visit Nola's coalescing
in the next video by.