When I first started learning javascript modules and that topic was the most confusing thing ever for
me.
I had a really tough time getting a grasp of the concept.
It took me a year to actually get it but I've created a mental image in my head to understand it better.
And as we do in this course we first start with the problem then go to the solution that we have now
to see where we where and where we are now.
This is the mental model that I've created and I call it climbing the mountain of modules.
Let me explain when we first started writing javascript and creating Web sites with JavaScript.
Well we had an ACM file and the very first time people were using JavaScript you used a script tag and
what we called an inline script and inline script is exactly that.
We just inline all of our javascript within the Asian email file.
Now there's problems that I see with this.
Imagine this getting massive a massive JavaScript file hundreds and thousands of lines of code.
One is the lack of code usability and you'll hear this term a lot if we need to add a another page maybe
an about iteration up page.
Well we have to copy this code and put it into the other Asian email file.
And the second was the pollution of the global namespace and that is once I use up a as a variable in
this case in the window object.
Well I can never use a again and maybe hundreds of lines down by mistake I assign a variable a and I
raise my a function.
Well that's a huge problem and that's a big problem in general.
You want to make sure that you don't pollute the global namespace that is the window object with all
these names because then you have collisions you have different team members working on different pieces
of the code and all of a sudden we both come up with the same name.
It's a big problem the next attempt was script X and this is something we've been familiar with.
Instead of having in line we had script X and where we played around with bootstrap and J query.
This is what we did.
We had our J query file load first then our JavaScript file load a second and as you can see we can
have one script file then the second one then the third one then the fourth one this way you have everything
outside of the issue email solves the problem write well.
The problem with script tags as far as I can see are three things if we need to add another page like
an about page well we still have to copy and paste this script ex and again we don't really want to
do that.
The second one is the lack of dependency resolution and that is you're responsible to make sure that
the scripts are added in proper order.
For example if this script accesses a function from the number for Doug James firewall it's going to
fail because the number for J.S. file hasn't loaded yet.
So that's lack of dependency resolution and finally a third.
This doesn't really solve the global namespace problem right.
It's polluting the global namespace all the functions and variables that are declared in each of these
files will be on the window object.
OK so what about the third attempt.
The IFC that stands for immediately invoked function execution.
I know that's a mouthful but it looks something like this.
And if he is it actually wraps a function in brackets so that JavaScript breathes this and says oh I
have to evaluate this and execute this and then these brackets at the end says run the function.
So after you evaluate this run this function and it was a confusing way to make sure of one thing and
that is by using this method you don't pollute the global namespace.
Now if in the first file you have variable my app they'll be on the window object but everything else
that's inside a function as we know creates a new scope.
So all the files because they're wrapped in this.
If he had their own scope and if you wanted to add to my app you just added everything as a property
or a method so awesome that reduced our global namespace to just one.
I mean it's not zero but the one that's that's a lot better right.
But there is still one issue with this the order of the files are still important.
And I've worked on apps before where we're using so many scripts that this was close to 100 skip Dex.
And every time you need added a file you had to make sure that you added in the right place because
that file might be dependent on another file loading before it.
So as we know that's lack of dependency resolution.
And frankly this doesn't look very pretty so then we had browser certify this nice looking logo.
Now what did browser fi do.
It actually used something called common G Yes.
So I'm going to comment that if you go out and show you what browser if I did use common G yes which
allowed us to use a certain syntax and it looks something like this if I wanted to have on my first
JavaScript file a function ad I can say module dot exports and now in the second JavaScript file I could
require the ad must fix the strings here and now I can add add function into my javascript to file now
browser if I use this common syntax but it's actually a module bundler.
And what does that mean.
Well it runs before you put the Web site online.
What that means is it read to all the JavaScript files rescue all the syntax and it bundles everything
into a single file once you run all the files through browser Fi and again is just a simple tool that
allowed us to just dump all our script files all of these into browser Fi and as long as we use the
common syntax like this it will know what to do and automatically create one file usually be called
something like bundled that J.S. so all our scripts will just be on one massive file and yeah that might
be bad when we're actually developing.
But when it's out on the Internet in real world we don't really care how it looks because we're just
doing this to send it somewhere to a server so that the web app can be viewed by users.
That's not what it's actually going to look when developers are working on it.
When developers are working on it we just have our own separate files.
We just run it through browser fi right before we deploy that is put it out to the public.
All right.
So that was pretty cool and we're getting closer to the top of the mountain here.
Now all of these problems here it was all because javascript didn't have what we call a module system
built into the language and think of modules as building blocks as different pieces of code.
So instead of having one giant thing you have modules.
Each piece is really really good at doing one thing and because javascript didn't have this module system.
It's the reason we have so many different ways of importing and exporting modules and there's actually
quite a few more that I didn't show because well frankly it'll just be too much but things have recently
changed with the introduction of E6.
We can now do something a lot nicer and it looks something like this with iOS 6.
We have two new things export and import for example in JavaScript one file.
I can have a function and you can see them using air functions here an add function and I simply export
it or I can even do export default in the second file if I wanted to use the add function.
All I say is import and then we see here the disk structuring.
You might remember this from the iOS five iOS 6 video and we're simply just grabbing had or if the export
was default which means with this you can export multiple functions in the same file versus here you
can only export one thing so the file only exports one thing.
Well in that case we don't need the lower brackets we can just do add from that file.
Very cool so that's nice.
That reads pretty nicely.
We just put the imports at the top so each file we know exactly what each file needs and everything
is clean everything's works and we don't have to worry about any of this stuff right.
Well yeah kind of.
As you know by now and I feel like a broken record browsers aren't supporting everything yet because
it's a new feature.
Again we're still waiting on browsers to implement them.
But this is what this blue thing is for.
It's called the [REMOVED] and [REMOVED].
Just like browser certify is a module bundler that is a bundles modules which is bundles JavaScript
files and just like browser fi it traverses the dependency tree which is these export and import tags
into a single file or it can even have multiple files based on your needs and with [REMOVED] we can actually
use E6 in all browsers.
Isn't that awesome.
This is where we are now we've climbed the mountain of modules and we have a really really good system
right now in JavaScript.
It was really hard getting there but we're in a good place right now.
So this is what we're gonna be using.
And this is what the industry is using.
Get used to this syntax.
I'll leave a link at the end of this video so you can check out more.
But when we get to react we're gonna be using this a lot and it's gonna be a ton of fun it's gonna make
things really nice and clean for us.
One thing I wanted to show you.
You might think hey this [REMOVED] thing seems like it's kind of hard.
Like how does it do it.
It's very simple it just has a config file just like this.
As you can see we just have an output that is bundle that J us and we don't need to worry too much about
it.
Usually when somebody is starting a project it's one person on the team that configured this file and
everything is done the rest.
You just build on top of it's very very simple to get started.
I don't think it's super important for us to tackle right now but again a very very useful tool and
it creates a nice bundle J File so now all our AC Mills look nice and simple and you know what.
That's it.
We've covered some of the most important topics in JavaScript and some really really hard topics and
I know your brain is hurting from all this information.
But you've done it.
We've finished the section and previous sections and now we can actually build amazing apps with the
tools that we have.
Can't wait to show you how all these pieces come together to build something amazing.
I'll see in the next video by.